<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss  xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" 
      xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" 
      xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" 
      xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" 
      version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>An Abundant Life</title>
<link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/index.html</link>
<atom:link href="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<description></description>
<generator>quarto-1.2.269</generator>
<lastBuildDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:00:00 GMT</lastBuildDate>
<item>
  <title>My Memories of Spencer</title>
  <dc:creator>Betsy Miller</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Betsy Miller/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<ul>
<li>When did you first meet Spencer (Elder Irvine)?</li>
</ul>
<p>I believe I first met Elder Irvine in 2009. I was in Van Nuys Ward at that time.</p>
<hr>
<ul>
<li>What was your impression when you first met Elder Irvine and Erickson?</li>
</ul>
<p>When I opened my door, I felt like Elder Irvine and Elder Erickson were literally messengers from God.<br>
They radiated goodness and love, so sweet and kind and excited to share the Gospel with me.</p>
<hr>
<ul>
<li>Could you describe Elder Irvine reaction, when you told him, you have been waiting for them?</li>
</ul>
<p>Initially, I think my welcoming response, was totally unexpected to them.</p>
<p>And then he asked me why I said that.</p>
<p>I told him, I assumed my sister had given them my address.</p>
<p>She never gave up on me.</p>
<p>Cory, my sister, and I are very close.</p>
<p>She told me once that the only gift she wanted from me was to be temple worthy so I could be sealed to our parents.</p>
<p>My life had not been the best.</p>
<hr>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Betsy Miller/temple.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<ul>
<li>What helped (prepared) you to meet these Elders and welcome them into your home?</li>
</ul>
<p>There really was no preparation.<br>
I hadn’t consciously thought about it.</p>
<hr>
<ul>
<li>What was it about Elder Irvine that made you trust in him?</li>
</ul>
<p>Elder Irvine was one of the genuinely nicest people I ever met.<br>
He radiated the spirit of the Lord.<br>
He was truly concerned about me.</p>
<hr>
<ul>
<li>What Christ-like qualities did E. Irvine possess?</li>
</ul>
<p>Elder Irvine demonstrated these Christlike qualities</p>
<ol type="1">
<li>He loved our Heavenly Father.</li>
<li>He had charity in his heart,</li>
<li>He was kind to everyone.</li>
<li>He was reverent when teaching me.</li>
<li>He was an excellent teacher</li>
<li>He knew that his mission was a blessing from God.</li>
<li>Mostly, he was very patient with me.</li>
</ol>
<hr>
<ul>
<li>Do you recall an instance when Elder Irvine provided a Christ-like service?</li>
</ul>
<p>The day he gave me my scriptures I cried.</p>
<p>I hadn’t had my own scriptures for 30 years.</p>
<p>I cried when I read the inscription:</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“Dear Betsy,<br>
Great treasures of hidden wisdom are contained in this book.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I know the truths in the Book of Mormon, Doctrine and Covenants and Pearl of Great Price will sustain you in your life’s trials. God will always be there for us.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>You are great! God loves you. He wants you to be happy. He is your Father in Heaven. Take good care of yourself, and God will provide for you.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Love, Elder Spencer Irvine</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<ul>
<li>What do you think is the purpose of the missionary work, as practiced in the LDS church?</li>
</ul>
<p>I believe that missionary work is to provide a way for us to return to our Father in Heaven.<br>
It is up to us to listen and accept it.<br>
They need to be true examples of Christ in all they do.</p>
<hr>
<ul>
<li>Some words for the family of Elder Irvine.</li>
</ul>
<p>Even though Spencer was truly a messenger from God, he was also very funny.</p>
<p>When the missionaries were working with me, they were at my house three or four times a week. They helped me decorate for holidays..</p>
<p>He especially loved all my Halloween decorations.</p>
<p>Spencer taught me that even though I live by myself, I am never alone. My Savior is always with me.</p>
<p>As I write this tears stream down my face thinking of what the world has lost, but at the same time I am delighted in knowing Spencer is experiencing the Glory of God, as he continues to teach and waits to embrace those he loves as they join him in the eternities.</p>
<p>Thank you for this opportunity to express my feelings.<br>
Please give Don a hug for me, I truly enjoyed meeting him.</p>
<p>May God bless you all in your time of grief and know that he and Spencer are smiling down on us each and every day.</p>
<ul>
<li>Betsy Miller</li>
</ul>
<script src="https://utteranc.es/client.js" repo="https://github.com/spencerirvinereed/blogComment" issue-term="pathname" theme="github-light" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>



 ]]></description>
  <category>recollection</category>
  <category>testimony</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Betsy Miller/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Betsy Miller/temple.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Shot Clock Blog : Nov 2013 ~ Apr 2017</title>
  <dc:creator>Uncle David</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Shot Clock Blog/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>In the universe of sports and history coverage, there is no shortage of outlets that tells (and shows) what has happened.</p>
<p>Far less in supply are those that explain how and why it happened.</p>
<p>Even fewer are those that give meaning to the event as well as how it might apply to our daily lives.</p>
<hr>
<p>There are similarities between sports and history. It is possible to enjoy both as participants and as spectators.</p>
<p>That is why Spencer enjoyed and excelled in both. Because he was a student and a participant (in the case of football and other sports)</p>
<p>Both involve strategy and tactical implementation or execution.</p>
<p>The sport, a modern day warfare, is repeated each fall and on each Saturday two regional foes are able to claim victory, for a day, and for a season.</p>
<p>The immediacy of outcome, the sense of participation, and the consequence of defeat has been transported from a battlefield to a playing field.</p>
<hr>
<p>No better guide than Spencer, for either a tour of historical sites or as commentator of sports events.</p>
<p>In many ways, he was better than the internet offerings or even Chat GPT.</p>
<p>Because he would tailor his narrative to fit the audience – of one.</p>
<p>In this era of confusion and division, our own <code>Warring States (Ideas) Period</code>, Spencer provided a clear, logical, calming narrative.</p>
<p>A quote from a Chinese military general, strategist, philosopher, and writer who lived during the Eastern Zhou period (771 to 256 BC). <sup>1</sup></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>“If you know the enemy and know yourself, you need not fear the result of a hundred battles. If you know yourself but not the enemy, for every victory gained you will also suffer a defeat. If you know neither the enemy nor yourself, you will succumb in every battle.”</p>
</blockquote>
<p>― Sun Tzu, The Art of War</p>
<p>Thank you for researching, participating and enlightening our lives with your writing.</p>
<hr>
<p>Here are some entries from a blog about sports.</p>
<p><a href="https://shotclockblog.wordpress.com/">November 2013 to April 2017</a></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Welcome to the Shot Clock Blog, where we give quick sports analysis in under 24 seconds!</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>My brother Steven and I started this blog to write down our thoughts and observations of all major professional sports: NBA, NFL, NHL, MLB and major college sports (basketball and football).</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>We’re always game for advice, tips and especially comments and questions. If you have something that you’ve wondered about, comment and send it our way so we can do the legwork FOR YOU!</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>We hope you enjoy the Shot Clock Blog!</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<section id="soccer-analysis" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="soccer-analysis">Soccer Analysis</h2>
<p>Goal 2: Miroslav Klose</p>
<p>Jokes about him being “the Kloser” abounds, but he finishes the best within 8 yards of the goal. Now, he has 16 goals to lead all World Cup scorers and passed Brazil’s Ronaldo. His goal came off of a turnover in Brazil’s defensive half, where Kroos salvaged a poor pass and saw Muller racing across the front of the goal. <img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Shot Clock Blog/klose-goal-turnover.webp" class="img-fluid"> One pinpoint pass later, the defenders and goalkeeper Julio Cesar crash on Muller, but Muller drops the pass to the feet of Klose.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Shot Clock Blog/klose-goal-shot-on-goal.png" class="img-fluid"> Klose shoots, Cesar makes the first save but leaves a juicy rebound for Klose to finish. 2-0 Germany. Congrats on your 16th goal, Klose!</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Shot Clock Blog/klose-goal-celebration.png" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><a href="https://shotclockblog.wordpress.com/2014/07/08/worldcup2014-how-germany-destroyed-brazil-7-1-san-antonio-spurs-type-offense/">link</a></p>
</section>
<section id="ncaa-quarterbacks-august-2015-entry" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ncaa-quarterbacks-august-2015-entry">5 NCAA Quarterbacks: August 2015 Entry</h2>
<p><a href="https://shotclockblog.wordpress.com/2015/08/28/what-to-watch-for-five-ncaa-qbs-to-track-in-2015/">link</a></p>
<ol start="5" type="1">
<li>Taysom Hill, BYU</li>
</ol>
<p>He is a dark horse for the Heisman trophy, according to some, but he is just as dangerous as Tim Tebow was at Florida. Before a season-ending and gruesome injury at Utah State, Hill wowed college football fans and scouts with his running style and numbers (although many project him as a running back-type player in the NFL if he chooses to play/is drafted:</p>
<p>I mean, he did run rampant in the 2013 game against Texas and even hurdled a defender on a touchdown run last year:</p>
<div class="quarto-video ratio ratio-16x9"><iframe src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/9rG7QoUMGiI" title="" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>
<p>He’s coming back from tearing his knee, so no one is too sure if he’ll be the same. But, BYU’s independent schedule is intriguing and if they do well, it’ll be because of Taysom Hill. Everyone loves an underdog (see: Boise State).</p>
<script src="https://utteranc.es/client.js" repo="https://github.com/spencerirvinereed/blogComment" issue-term="pathname" theme="github-light" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>


</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://www.wikiwand.com/en/Sun_Tzu↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>sports</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Shot Clock Blog/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Shot Clock Blog/klose-goal-turnover.webp" medium="image" type="image/webp"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Spencer’s Testimony</title>
  <dc:creator>Spencer</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Last Testimony/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>The Lord will never lead us astray and He is always with us.</p>
<p>He has been with me during my trial and diagnosis of cancer.</p>
<p>And I know He will not abandon me.</p>
<p>He has shown me tender mercies with messages from friends of years past.</p>
<p>I have heard from people whom I love and respect as a youth and as an adult.<br>
I have felt my Savior’s love.<br>
I know He is real.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center" style="float:right;">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Last Testimony/young.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img" alt="At Marriage of an Aunt, 1994" width="201"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">At Mesa Temple, Aged 6</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>He exists.</p>
<p>And I know He loves me.</p>
<p>He is Jesus the Christ.</p>
<p>He is my loving Lord and Savior, even Redeemer of all mankind.</p>
<p>I look to Him and I shall live again. I know Him. I love Him.</p>
<p>In the sacred name of Jesus Christ, I testify of Him and pray. Amen.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center" style="float:right;">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Last Testimony/peak.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img" alt="At Marriage of a Friend" width="401"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">At a Wedding, Mid 20s</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>An excerpt from Spencer’s final scripture journal entry<br>
21 September 2023</p>
<script src="https://utteranc.es/client.js" repo="https://github.com/spencerirvinereed/blogComment" issue-term="pathname" theme="github-light" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>



 ]]></description>
  <category>testimony</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Last Testimony/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 05 Oct 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Last Testimony/young.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Harvest Gathering</title>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mid Autumn Festival/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>All cultures celebrate and give thanks during the harvest season.</p>
<p>The Wikipedia defines a Harvest Celebration as</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>A harvest festival is an annual celebration that occurs around the time of the main harvest of a given region</p>
</blockquote>
<p>For many in the northern Asia, the Harvest Festival is celebrated during the 8th Lunar Month, when the moon is full<sup>1</sup>.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mid Autumn Festival/roof_bw.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>For Koreans, of my generation, 추석(秋夕, Autumn Evening), or 한가위(the great middle (of autumn)) is a time of gathering, celebrating, remembering of ancestors.</p>
<p>The gathering is according to family units at the hometown for at least 3 days.</p>
<p>It is time of great feast, fresh harvest along with items normally set aside for special occasions.</p>
<p>It is a celebration if the harvest was sufficient to last the winter months, or when the next harvest can be expected – at least during the agrarian days.</p>
<p>Remembering the ancestors involves tidying up the grave and preparing a meal for the deceased and saying set phrases executing set movements.</p>
<hr>
<p>Normally, it is a time of anticipation and celebration, unless the person is one of over 8 million<sup>2</sup> 실향민 in South Korea.</p>
<p>실향민(失鄕民 / refugee), is also translated a <code>Displace People</code>. People who are unable to return to their homeland due to, usually, man-made, political boundaries.</p>
<p>Growing up, gathering during the Harvest Celebration, meant visiting the graves of the deceased and visiting the household with the oldest member of the clan.</p>
<p>Since my family migrated (or were refugees) from Northern part of Korea, the gathering was very small, the celebration was limited. We talked of old home (老家) and we yearned for the day when we can travel to the ancestral home and meet the people with common heritage.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mid Autumn Festival/old_home.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>That dream is still is alive.</p>
<p>However the probability of its occurrence is small. Even it was possible, what is the meaning of face to face meeting people with no interactions or knowledge of relationship – for nearly 75 years.</p>
<hr>
<p>Celebrating harvest celebration alone as a grown up was more challenging. Everyone took the, mandatory time off and headed to their hometown.</p>
<p>I, on the other hand, went and visited my only relative in Seoul – traveling in opposite direction than the vast majority of the population.</p>
<p>Living in the United States has been a dream of my parents. Most of the time, I relish the label of refugee/immigrant. A refugee within Korea followed by migration to the great land of America.</p>
<p>At times, especially during the time of family gathering to ancestral home, I wish to know the rest of people that I ought to know.</p>
<hr>
<section id="importance-of-physical-gathering" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="importance-of-physical-gathering">Importance of Physical Gathering</h2>
<p>Biblical patriarchs speaks of gathering unto the people. Similar expression are used in Korea, including the phrase, <code>돌아가다</code>, return to where one originated from.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>29 And he charged them, and said unto them, I am to be gathered unto my people: bury me with my fathers in the cave that is in the field of Ephron the Hittite,<sup>3</sup></p>
</blockquote>
<p>Our physical, mortal existence ends with a burial - a literal and a symbolic gathering. In Christianity, that symbolic burial of the body is followed by the literal gathering of spirits and souls, it is called the resurrection.</p>
</section>
<section id="necessity-of-spiritual-gathering" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="necessity-of-spiritual-gathering">Necessity of Spiritual Gathering</h2>
<p>Approaching the latter half of life, contemplating the eventual death and transformation, I begin to wonder and as I prepare,</p>
<ul>
<li>Will we be gathered and organized by the family groups.</li>
<li>What type of work will I be involved in</li>
<li>How will wrongs and lack of experiences due to premature death be corrected and extended.</li>
<li>What type of learning and how will furthering of our understanding happen</li>
</ul>
<hr>
</section>
<section id="kang-and-hwang-family-information" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="kang-and-hwang-family-information">Kang and Hwang Family Information</h2>
<section id="grandma-hwang-family-ancentral-home" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="grandma-hwang-family-ancentral-home">Grandma Hwang Family Ancentral Home</h3>
<p>평안남도 강서군 초리면 송호리<br>
황운학 김연화<br>
<sup>4</sup></p>
</section>
<section id="grandpa-kang-family-ancentral-home" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="grandpa-kang-family-ancentral-home">Grandpa Kang Family Ancentral Home</h3>
<p>함경남도 안변군 신모면 이남리<br>
강현용 김옥돌<br>
<sup>5</sup></p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mid Autumn Festival/roof_color.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Autumn Harvest 2023</p>
</blockquote>
<script src="https://utteranc.es/client.js" repo="https://github.com/spencerirvinereed/blogComment" issue-term="pathname" theme="github-light" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>


</section>
</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>The Full Moon is when the Sun and the Moon are aligned on opposite sides of Earth, and 100% of the Moon’s face is illuminated by the Sun, <a href="https://www.timeanddate.com/astronomy/moon/full-moon.html">link</a>↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>실향민의 숫자는 1985년 5백만명으로 집계됐으며, 2~3세까지 합하면 8백만명에 이른다고 한다, <a href="https://namu.wiki/w/%EC%8B%A4%ED%96%A5%EB%AF%BC">link</a>↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>https://www.biblegateway.com/passage/?search=Genesis%2049&amp;version=KJV↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn4"><p>From the memory of mother Hwang↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn5"><p>Family Census Record, original in Korean/Chinese↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>gratitude</category>
  <category>gathering</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mid Autumn Festival/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 02 Oct 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mid Autumn Festival/roof_bw.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Married Years - 2017 - 2023</title>
  <dc:creator>Irvine &amp; Nunez Family</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Married Years - 2017 - 2023/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="april-2019" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="april-2019">April 2019</h2>
<p>Moving from Maryland to Arizona.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Married Years - 2017 - 2023/moving_truck.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="bree-and-stevens-wedding" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="bree-and-stevens-wedding">Bree and Steven’s Wedding</h2>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Married Years - 2017 - 2023/steven_wedding.jpeg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Steven &amp; Bree</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Married Years - 2017 - 2023/steven_wedding2.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Steven &amp; Bree"> <a href="https://photos.app.goo.gl/wSDb2qjJ2Qswy8yu7">More photos</a></p>
</section>
<section id="noeline-nuñez" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="noeline-nuñez">Noeline Nuñez</h2>
<p>You are so young to be taken away from us so soon.</p>
<p>Our hearts ache, especially for Meg, on your sudden passing.</p>
<p>The aggressive and extremely rare form of pancreatic cancer you were diagnosed with less than a month ago was a huge curveball no one ever saw coming.</p>
<p>We feel extra sad that you never even had the chance to fight your disease, but relieved at the same time that you no longer will be in so much pain.</p>
<p>I first met you during rehearsal dinner the night before your wedding day to my niece on Thanksgiving weekend 2017.</p>
<p>After that, we’ve had a lot of good conversations and exchanges of opinions on different topics every time we meet on family gatherings since you became part of our clan.</p>
<p>You’re such an intelligent person and I enjoyed all our conversations.</p>
<p>And you have this habit of pushing the middle part of your eyeglasses up your nose bridge with your forefinger.</p>
<p>I have witnessed how you look after and took care of Meg that I remembered she even honored you with an award for best in husbandship category.</p>
<p>You are a great guy and a wonderful human being.</p>
<p>I relished all the conversations we had over the few years I’ve known you and the add-on comments you typically make that shone light on your being a history buff.</p>
<p>I still have the email you sent me in 2021 with detailed itineraries for my planned trip to the DC area.</p>
<p>I will make that trip and follow your guide in your honor.</p>
<p>My trip to AZ this coming weekend was long ago planned for Layla’s 1st birthday and I was looking forward to our usual board and trivia games.</p>
<p>Instead I’ll be seeing you this time at your funeral services.🥲</p>
<p>Thank you, Spence, for the time you have spent with us. Your time on this earth may have been short, but your wonderful memories will remain with us forever.</p>
<p>Our lives are extra special for having been blessed with your wonderful presence.</p>
<p>You will be so dearly missed.</p>
<p>Soar high, Spence. We love you.❤️</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Married Years - 2017 - 2023/journey_begun.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="arianne-hidalgo" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="arianne-hidalgo">Arianne Hidalgo</h2>
<p>Yesterday, my brother-in-law Spencer (Meg’s husband), passed away.</p>
<p>He was battling an aggressive and extremely rare type of pancreatic cancer that has led to multiple organ failure.</p>
<p>He was 35 years young and we only found out about his diagnosis about a month ago.</p>
<p>His decline was SO rapid (he hasn’t started chemo) that all of us are in disbelief but we are so thankful for family and friends who were able to come at such short notice.</p>
<p>He passed away peacefully surrounded by family.</p>
<p>Meg’s strength amazes me.</p>
<p>She has stepped up and took great care of Spencer.</p>
<p>My baby sister loved her husband fiercely and this has been so heartbreaking for all us.</p>
<p>Love you, Spencer Irvine!</p>
<p>Thank you for being SO good to Meg and to all of us, for loving my kids and being who you are.</p>
<p>You are loved by so, so many! ❤️</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Married Years - 2017 - 2023/meg_spencer.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>blog</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Married Years - 2017 - 2023/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Married Years - 2017 - 2023/moving_truck.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Video : Washington DC North Mission</title>
  <dc:creator>President &amp; Sister Neilson</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/video_tribute/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Hi President &amp; Sister Irvine, 💗</p>
<p>I just wanted to write you a note and tell you how thankful I am for you and for having you as such amazing senior missionaries.</p>
<p>I loved the aprons &amp; always delicious food &amp; acts of service &amp; love while I was in Washington D.C.!</p>
<p>I especially loved the sack lunches you would make us for zone conferences &amp; the handmade masks when I was brand new to the mission back in august of 2020.</p>
<p>They made me have so much joy! 💗</p>
<p>I was so sad to hear about your son passing away.</p>
<p>I am praying for you &amp; Sister Irvine &amp; your family and hope you have comfort &amp; peace.</p>
<p>Thank you for making missionary life better in a time that a lot of the time felt really dark &amp; dreary.</p>
<p>I hope you &amp; your family are able to feel loved &amp; fortified.</p>
<p>💗 love you</p>
<p>President &amp; Sister Irvine!!! 💗</p>
<ul>
<li>Sister <code>D</code></li>
</ul>
<hr>
<p>Elder and Sister Irvine!</p>
<p>We’re so sorry for your loss😢 we know he’s in Jesus’s hand now, God has a plan for him!</p>
<p>Keep being strong, you are in our prayers.</p>
<p>We love you🤟</p>
<hr>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/video_tribute/Full.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>President Reid &amp; Shelly Neilson (2019-2022) and missionaries that served in the Washington DC North Mission.</p>
<div class="callout-note callout callout-style-default callout-captioned">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-caption-container flex-fill">
The video contains audio, may need to adjust volume accordingly
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">

</div>
</div>
<figure class="figure">
<figcaption class="figure-caption">
Click to listen
</figcaption>
<video controls="" src="Full.MOV">
<p>Your browser does not support the <code>video</code> element.</p>
</video>
</figure>
<script src="https://utteranc.es/client.js" repo="https://github.com/spencerirvinereed/blogComment" issue-term="pathname" theme="github-light" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>



 ]]></description>
  <category>video_message</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/video_tribute/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/video_tribute/Full.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>The Funeral Service</title>
  <dc:creator>Camelview Ward, Scottsdale Camelback Stake</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230930 The Funeral/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230930 The Funeral/sunrise2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230930 The Funeral/program2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<section id="sequence" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sequence">Sequence</h2>
<div class="cell">
<div class="cell-output-display">

<div id="httlnyhirp" style="padding-left:0px;padding-right:0px;padding-top:10px;padding-bottom:10px;overflow-x:auto;overflow-y:auto;width:auto;height:auto;">
<style>#httlnyhirp table {
  font-family: system-ui, 'Segoe UI', Roboto, Helvetica, Arial, sans-serif, 'Apple Color Emoji', 'Segoe UI Emoji', 'Segoe UI Symbol', 'Noto Color Emoji';
  -webkit-font-smoothing: antialiased;
  -moz-osx-font-smoothing: grayscale;
}

#httlnyhirp thead, #httlnyhirp tbody, #httlnyhirp tfoot, #httlnyhirp tr, #httlnyhirp td, #httlnyhirp th {
  border-style: none;
}

#httlnyhirp p {
  margin: 0;
  padding: 0;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_table {
  display: table;
  border-collapse: collapse;
  line-height: normal;
  margin-left: auto;
  margin-right: auto;
  color: #333333;
  font-size: 16px;
  font-weight: normal;
  font-style: normal;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  width: auto;
  border-top-style: solid;
  border-top-width: 2px;
  border-top-color: #A8A8A8;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 2px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #A8A8A8;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 2px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_caption {
  padding-top: 4px;
  padding-bottom: 4px;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_title {
  color: #333333;
  font-size: 125%;
  font-weight: initial;
  padding-top: 4px;
  padding-bottom: 4px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  border-bottom-color: #FFFFFF;
  border-bottom-width: 0;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_subtitle {
  color: #333333;
  font-size: 85%;
  font-weight: initial;
  padding-top: 3px;
  padding-bottom: 5px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  border-top-color: #FFFFFF;
  border-top-width: 0;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_heading {
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  text-align: center;
  border-bottom-color: #FFFFFF;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 1px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 1px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_bottom_border {
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_col_headings {
  border-top-style: solid;
  border-top-width: 2px;
  border-top-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 1px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 1px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_col_heading {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  font-size: 100%;
  font-weight: normal;
  text-transform: inherit;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 1px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 1px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
  vertical-align: bottom;
  padding-top: 5px;
  padding-bottom: 6px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  overflow-x: hidden;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_column_spanner_outer {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  font-size: 100%;
  font-weight: normal;
  text-transform: inherit;
  padding-top: 0;
  padding-bottom: 0;
  padding-left: 4px;
  padding-right: 4px;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_column_spanner_outer:first-child {
  padding-left: 0;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_column_spanner_outer:last-child {
  padding-right: 0;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_column_spanner {
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
  vertical-align: bottom;
  padding-top: 5px;
  padding-bottom: 5px;
  overflow-x: hidden;
  display: inline-block;
  width: 100%;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_spanner_row {
  border-bottom-style: hidden;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_group_heading {
  padding-top: 8px;
  padding-bottom: 8px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  font-size: 100%;
  font-weight: initial;
  text-transform: inherit;
  border-top-style: solid;
  border-top-width: 2px;
  border-top-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 1px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 1px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
  vertical-align: middle;
  text-align: left;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_empty_group_heading {
  padding: 0.5px;
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  font-size: 100%;
  font-weight: initial;
  border-top-style: solid;
  border-top-width: 2px;
  border-top-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
  vertical-align: middle;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_from_md > :first-child {
  margin-top: 0;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_from_md > :last-child {
  margin-bottom: 0;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_row {
  padding-top: 8px;
  padding-bottom: 8px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  margin: 10px;
  border-top-style: solid;
  border-top-width: 1px;
  border-top-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 1px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 1px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
  vertical-align: middle;
  overflow-x: hidden;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_stub {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  font-size: 100%;
  font-weight: initial;
  text-transform: inherit;
  border-right-style: solid;
  border-right-width: 2px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_stub_row_group {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  font-size: 100%;
  font-weight: initial;
  text-transform: inherit;
  border-right-style: solid;
  border-right-width: 2px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  vertical-align: top;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_row_group_first td {
  border-top-width: 2px;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_row_group_first th {
  border-top-width: 2px;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_summary_row {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  text-transform: inherit;
  padding-top: 8px;
  padding-bottom: 8px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_first_summary_row {
  border-top-style: solid;
  border-top-color: #D3D3D3;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_first_summary_row.thick {
  border-top-width: 2px;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_last_summary_row {
  padding-top: 8px;
  padding-bottom: 8px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_grand_summary_row {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  text-transform: inherit;
  padding-top: 8px;
  padding-bottom: 8px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_first_grand_summary_row {
  padding-top: 8px;
  padding-bottom: 8px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  border-top-style: double;
  border-top-width: 6px;
  border-top-color: #D3D3D3;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_last_grand_summary_row_top {
  padding-top: 8px;
  padding-bottom: 8px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
  border-bottom-style: double;
  border-bottom-width: 6px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_striped {
  background-color: rgba(128, 128, 128, 0.05);
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_table_body {
  border-top-style: solid;
  border-top-width: 2px;
  border-top-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-bottom-style: solid;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_footnotes {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  border-bottom-style: none;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 2px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 2px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_footnote {
  margin: 0px;
  font-size: 90%;
  padding-top: 4px;
  padding-bottom: 4px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_sourcenotes {
  color: #333333;
  background-color: #FFFFFF;
  border-bottom-style: none;
  border-bottom-width: 2px;
  border-bottom-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-left-style: none;
  border-left-width: 2px;
  border-left-color: #D3D3D3;
  border-right-style: none;
  border-right-width: 2px;
  border-right-color: #D3D3D3;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_sourcenote {
  font-size: 90%;
  padding-top: 4px;
  padding-bottom: 4px;
  padding-left: 5px;
  padding-right: 5px;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_left {
  text-align: left;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_center {
  text-align: center;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_right {
  text-align: right;
  font-variant-numeric: tabular-nums;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_font_normal {
  font-weight: normal;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_font_bold {
  font-weight: bold;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_font_italic {
  font-style: italic;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_super {
  font-size: 65%;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_footnote_marks {
  font-size: 75%;
  vertical-align: 0.4em;
  position: initial;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_asterisk {
  font-size: 100%;
  vertical-align: 0;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_indent_1 {
  text-indent: 5px;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_indent_2 {
  text-indent: 10px;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_indent_3 {
  text-indent: 15px;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_indent_4 {
  text-indent: 20px;
}

#httlnyhirp .gt_indent_5 {
  text-indent: 25px;
}
</style>
<table class="gt_table" data-quarto-disable-processing="false" data-quarto-bootstrap="false">
  <thead>
    
    <tr class="gt_col_headings">
      <th class="gt_col_heading gt_columns_bottom_border gt_right" rowspan="1" colspan="1" scope="col" id="Time">Time</th>
      <th class="gt_col_heading gt_columns_bottom_border gt_left" rowspan="1" colspan="1" scope="col" id="Program">Program</th>
      <th class="gt_col_heading gt_columns_bottom_border gt_left" rowspan="1" colspan="1" scope="col" id="Person">Person</th>
    </tr>
  </thead>
  <tbody class="gt_table_body">
    <tr><td headers="Time" class="gt_row gt_right">0:00</td>
<td headers="Program" class="gt_row gt_left">Welcome</td>
<td headers="Person" class="gt_row gt_left">Bishop McCormack</td></tr>
    <tr><td headers="Time" class="gt_row gt_right">0:50</td>
<td headers="Program" class="gt_row gt_left">How Great Thou Art</td>
<td headers="Person" class="gt_row gt_left">Congregation</td></tr>
    <tr><td headers="Time" class="gt_row gt_right">5:40</td>
<td headers="Program" class="gt_row gt_left">Opening Prayer</td>
<td headers="Person" class="gt_row gt_left">Bary Turley</td></tr>
    <tr><td headers="Time" class="gt_row gt_right">8:15</td>
<td headers="Program" class="gt_row gt_left">Tribute</td>
<td headers="Person" class="gt_row gt_left">Kristy Tidwell</td></tr>
    <tr><td headers="Time" class="gt_row gt_right">20:15</td>
<td headers="Program" class="gt_row gt_left">My Shepherd</td>
<td headers="Person" class="gt_row gt_left">Gonzales</td></tr>
    <tr><td headers="Time" class="gt_row gt_right">24:30</td>
<td headers="Program" class="gt_row gt_left">Tribute</td>
<td headers="Person" class="gt_row gt_left">Steven Irvine</td></tr>
    <tr><td headers="Time" class="gt_row gt_right">36:00</td>
<td headers="Program" class="gt_row gt_left">Tribute</td>
<td headers="Person" class="gt_row gt_left">Alfredo Lopez</td></tr>
    <tr><td headers="Time" class="gt_row gt_right">51:30</td>
<td headers="Program" class="gt_row gt_left">Families Can be Together</td>
<td headers="Person" class="gt_row gt_left">Family</td></tr>
    <tr><td headers="Time" class="gt_row gt_right">54:30</td>
<td headers="Program" class="gt_row gt_left">Remarks</td>
<td headers="Person" class="gt_row gt_left">Bishop McCormack</td></tr>
    <tr><td headers="Time" class="gt_row gt_right">1:05:15</td>
<td headers="Program" class="gt_row gt_left">Battle Hymn</td>
<td headers="Person" class="gt_row gt_left">Congregation</td></tr>
    <tr><td headers="Time" class="gt_row gt_right">1:07:35</td>
<td headers="Program" class="gt_row gt_left">Closing Prayer</td>
<td headers="Person" class="gt_row gt_left">Elijah Nunez</td></tr>
  </tbody>
  
  
</table>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="sec-great_thou" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sec-great_thou">How Great Thou Art<sup>1</sup></h2>
<ol type="1">
<li>O Lord my God, when I in awesome wonder Consider all the <em>worlds thy hands have made, I see the stars, I hear the</em> rolling thunder, Thy pow’r thru-out the universe displayed;</li>
</ol>
<p>[Chorus]</p>
<p><em>Then sings my soul, my Savior God, to thee, How great thou art! How great thou art! Then sings my soul, my Savior God, to thee, How great thou art! How great thou art!</em></p>
<ol start="2" type="1">
<li><p>When thru the woods and forest glades I wander, And hear the birds sing sweetly in the trees, When I look down from lofty mountain grandeur And hear the brook and feel the gentle breeze, [Chorus]</p></li>
<li><p>And when I think that God, his Son not sparing, Sent him to die, I scarce can take it in, That on the cross, my burden gladly bearing, He bled and died to take away my sin, [Chorus]</p></li>
<li><p>When Christ shall come, with shout of acclamation, And take me home, what joy shall fill my heart! Then I shall bow in humble adoration And there proclaim, “My God, how great thou art!” [Chorus]</p></li>
</ol>
</section>
<section id="families-can-be-together-forever2" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="families-can-be-together-forever2">Families can be Together, Forever<sup>2</sup></h2>
<p>I have a fam’ly here on earth.</p>
<p>They are so good to me.</p>
<p>I want to share my life with them through all eternity.</p>
<p>[Chorus]</p>
<p><em>Fam’lies can be together forever</em></p>
<p><em>Through Heav’nly Father’s plan.</em></p>
<p><em>I always want to be with my own family,</em></p>
<p><em>And the Lord has shown me how I can.</em></p>
<p><em>The Lord has shown me how I can.</em></p>
<p>While I am in my early years,</p>
<p>I’ll prepare most carefully,</p>
<p>So I can marry in God’s temple for eternity.</p>
</section>
<section id="battle-hymn-of-the-republic3" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="battle-hymn-of-the-republic3">Battle Hymn of the Republic<sup>3</sup></h2>
<p>Mine eyes have seen the glory Of the coming of the Lord; He is trampling out the vintage Where the grapes of wrath are stored; He hath loosed the fateful lightning Of His terrible swift sword; His truth is marching on.</p>
<p>Chorus</p>
<p><em>Glory! Glory! Hallelujah! Glory! Glory! Hallelujah! Glory! Glory! Hallelujah! His truth is marching on.</em></p>
<p>I have seen Him in the watchfires Of a hundred circling camps They have builded Him an altar In the evening dews and damps; I can read His righteous sentence By the dim and flaring lamps; His day is marching on.</p>
<p><em>Chorus Glory! Glory! Hallelujah! Glory! Glory! Hallelujah! Glory! Glory! Hallelujah! His truth is marching on.</em></p>
<p>He has sounded forth the trumpet That shall never call retreat; He is sifting out the hearts of men Before His judgement seat; Oh, be swift, my soul, to answer Him; Be jubilant, my feet; Our God is marching on.</p>
<p><em>Chorus Glory! Glory! Hallelujah! Glory! Glory! Hallelujah! Glory! Glory! Hallelujah! His truth is marching on</em>.</p>
<p>In the beauty of the lilies Christ was born across the sea, With a glory in His bosom That transfigures you and me; As He died to make men holy, Let us die to make men free; While God is marching on.</p>
<p><em>Chorus Glory! Glory! Hallelujah! Glory! Glory! Hallelujah! Glory! Glory! Hallelujah! His truth is marching on</em>.</p>
<div class="callout-note callout callout-style-default callout-captioned">
<div class="callout-header d-flex align-content-center">
<div class="callout-icon-container">
<i class="callout-icon"></i>
</div>
<div class="callout-caption-container flex-fill">
These files contains audio, may need to adjust volume accordingly. Also note that the recording of hymns have less fidelity than the recording of speakers.
</div>
</div>
<div class="callout-body-container callout-body">

</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="audio-recording" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="audio-recording">Audio Recording</h2>
<figure class="figure">
<figcaption class="figure-caption">
Click to Listen
</figcaption>
<video controls="" src="full_recording.mp3">
<p>Your browser does not support the <code>video</code> element.</p>
</video>
</figure>
</section>
<section id="video-recording" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="video-recording">Video Recording</h2>
<p><a href="https://zoom.us/rec/share/L5Ihxve8iWl8dJ4kON-dJqW1cYdH1w6WJbNQohGnX_nA7wTda-ywE2_R3E9ZuuTk.VaY52zecFbg8Xaxd?iet=kPac2FZC5Pa6jFlUE1H-B4t3Ya7L1S65irqT6ODcTFw.AG.Uwp7h3h6VdnIuZkILyKtLsQHMLIuWjRcHjxjRC_XhGzhJpR0JjI9scqo3L2Tx6Aetgn7sphd9ifZCJR0DRraC_v-A_Oo1M9Mcv9POaSErnofY-5c2oWt-ykag5XqsA.s021rntHoL5nwx-CkZXbZA.FJR_Z8wXYgsem4o0">Link to Zoom Recording</a></p>
</section>
<section id="transcript" class="level1">
<h1>Transcript</h1>
<section id="bishop-mccormack" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="bishop-mccormack">Bishop McCormack</h2>
<p>Brothers and Sisters, family and friends.</p>
<p>Welcome to the Camelview Ward and a celebration of the life of Spencer Irvine.</p>
<p>My name is Bishop McCormack and presiding at this service is President Bruce from the stake presidency. And he has asked me to conduct.</p>
<p>A warm thank you to Brandon Turley for playing the piano and to Bree Irvine. She’ll be conducting the music.</p>
<p>We’ll begin this service by saying hymn number #86, How Great Thou Art. Following we will have our opening prayer by Barry Turley.</p>
</section>
<section id="opening-prayer---bary-turley" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="opening-prayer---bary-turley">Opening Prayer - Bary Turley</h2>
<p>Our Father in Heaven.</p>
<p>We are grateful for this opportunity. We have to come and celebrate, the life of Spencer Irvine.</p>
<p>We’re grateful for the opportunity that we’ve had to be a part of his life. To feel of his spirit and to feel of his love.</p>
<p>We ask thee to, please bless us that we may be able to. Have thy peace and comfort with us as we strive to reconcile this tragic passing.</p>
<p>Please help us to, use it as a catalyst to. Become better. Better families,individuals and more Christ like – as Spencer was.</p>
<p>We are grateful for the many blessings that Thou gives us for the gospel, For the Knowledge and comfort that we will one day be able to. See and be With him again, and</p>
<p>We say these things humbly in the name of Jesus Christ, Amen.</p>
</section>
<section id="bishop-mccormack-1" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="bishop-mccormack-1">Bishop McCormack</h2>
<p>We have a few speakers this morning.</p>
<p>First, the tribute to Spencer by his sister, Kristy Tidwell.</p>
<p>We will then pause to hear John and Sarah Gonzales singing my shepherd.</p>
<p>Following the musical number, a eulogy will be given by Steven Irvine. Following Stephen, Alfredo Lopez, (Spencer’s friend), will say a few words.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230930 The Funeral/fall1.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="kristy-irvine" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="kristy-irvine">Kristy Irvine</h2>
<p>My hope and prayer today is that the the spirit can be with me.</p>
<p>To help me get through this.</p>
<p>It took a long time for me to think about how I could give Spencer, a proper tribute to, who he was.</p>
<p>My dear brother Spencer left this mortality too soon, but not without making his mark in this world.</p>
<p>He lived his life in accordance with the principles that he knew to be true and aligned his life with the will of our savior Jesus Christ.</p>
<p>I think that it can be said of him, that like Nephi</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I glory in plainness,<br>
I glory in truth, I glory in my Jesus, for he hath redeemed my soul.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Spencer loved the Gospel of Jesus Christ and embodied it, and in all that he did. Even as a child, he could recognize true principles and devoted his life to the savior and our Heavenly Father.</p>
<p>He was a black and white kind of guy. He could see right. And he knew when things were wrong.</p>
<p>One of my favorite things that we talked about this week was, that even in preschool, when he was interviewed for a new story about missing school, he told the reporter that he missed school because he wanted to play.</p>
<p>And those were facts.</p>
<p>There’s a small section of a talk given by Michelle Craig that I would like to read because we can insert Spencer’s name into it and see him in it, she says.</p>
<hr>
<p>“When hard times come, I try to remember that I chose to follow Christ before I came to Earth and that challenges to my faith, my health and my endurance are all part of the reason I’m here.</p>
<p>And I certainly should never think that today’s trial calls into question God’s love for me or let it turn my faith in him into doubt.</p>
<p>Trials do not mean that the plan is failing.</p>
<p>They are part of the plan, meant to help me seek God.</p>
<p>I become more like him when I endure patiently and hopefully like him when in agony.</p>
<p>I pray more earnestly.</p>
<p>Jesus Christ was the perfect example of loving our father with all his heart, of doing his will and regardless of the cost, I want to follow his his example by doing the same”</p>
<hr>
<p>Spencer embodied so many Christ-like attributes throughout his short time here on Earth.</p>
<p>He was full of faith in Jesus Christ.</p>
<p>He fully accepted him as his personal Savior and Redeemer, and looked to Him in all things.</p>
<p>In <code>Preach My Gospel</code>, which is a guide for all members of the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
<p>It says that faith leads to action, and when you have faith in Jesus Christ, you accomplish what the Lord wants you to accomplish. And you help bring about good in your own life and the lives of others.</p>
<p>Spencer was always doing good in his life. He served others.</p>
<p>He remembered birthdays. He apologized for not remembering birthdays.</p>
<p>And he was always one to help when needed. Spencer was full of hope. He hoped for a better future for himself and Meg, and always look forward, not back.</p>
<p>He was patient, optimistic and persevered through his multiple surgeries, injuries, his recent diagnosis.</p>
<p>And in every trial that he faced, his eye was fixed firmly upon the Savior.</p>
<p>President James E Faust taught, <code>hope is the anchor of our souls</code>.</p>
<p>Spencer lived his life full of hope.</p>
<p>A man once asked Jesus which is the great commandment in the law.</p>
<p>Jesus replied,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Thou shalt love the Lord thy God with all thy heart, and with all thy soul, and with all thy mind. This is the first and great commandment, and the second is like unto it. Thou shalt love thy neighbor as thyself.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Spencer did this his entire life.</p>
<p>He put the Lord first.</p>
<p>His friends knew what he stood for and what he wouldn’t say or do.</p>
<p>Spencer listened to those around him and loved them unconditionally.</p>
<p>He served a full time mission in California, and his letters were always full of love for those around him.</p>
<p>Whenever I would text Spencer, he was quick to offer a kind word.</p>
<p>He supported me with love and was slow to anger.</p>
<p>His life was a life of charity, the pure love of Christ was part of who he was.</p>
<p>Spencer was a true disciple of Christ.</p>
<p>Elder De Feo. said in a talk entitled <code>Pure Love</code>, the true sign of every disciple of Jesus Christ said<sup>4</sup>.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>True disciples love to submit themselves to the Lord with peace in their heart. They are humble and submissive because they love him. They have faith to fully accept his will, not only in what he does, but also in how and when.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>True disciples know that the real blessings are not always what they want, but rather what the Lord wants for them.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>His humility and willingness to submit to the will of The Lord was and is inspiring.</p>
<p>Spencer went through periods of unemployment which to us is very disappointing and many when faced with this challenge can become despondent and even quick to anger with the Lord for not helping answer prayers for good employment.</p>
<p>Spencer did everything that he could to provide for himself and Meg, even taking jobs that were not equal to his education or talents.</p>
<p>But they were jobs that would allow him to provide. His humility and submission to the Lord, yielded great results with a job that Spencer truly loved.</p>
<p>Elder De Feo also said <code>pure love is the true sign of every true disciple of Jesus Christ</code>.</p>
<p>I’m sure many of you have memories of Spencer embodying this statement. His love was pure, it was unfettered from judgment and hostility.</p>
<p>He was a happy person who loved unconditionally.</p>
<p>He laughed with so many, he welcomed all.</p>
<p>He threw himself into youth activities and was always the first to offer a smile, tell a good joke and ask if anyone needed help.</p>
<p>Spencer loved his family.</p>
<p>He devoted his time to his sweetheart, Meg, and gave her everything that he could offer and the circumstances that they lived in.</p>
<p>He loved everything about his nieces and nephews.</p>
<p>And would gush over their photos and celebrate their accomplishments and encourage them when I would tell him of a struggle in their life.</p>
<p>In closing, I want to share a few thoughts on the resurrection. As we look to that day with longing and hope of seeing our dear Spencer again</p>
<p>The following is taken from a talk called <code>Sunday Will Come</code>, by Elder Wirthlin<sup>5</sup>.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>President Joseph F. Smith said “that those from whom we have to part here, we will meet again and see as they are. We will meet the same identical being that we associated with here in the flesh.”</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>President Spencer W. Kimball amplified this when he said, “I am sure that if we can imagine ourselves at our very best, physically, mentally, spiritually, that is the way we will come back.”</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p>“When Christ rose from the grave, becoming the first fruits of the Resurrection, He made that gift available to all. And with that sublime act, He softened the devastating, consuming sorrow that gnaws at the souls of those who have lost precious loved ones.</p>
<p>I think of how dark that Friday was when Christ was lifted up on the cross.</p>
<p>On that terrible Friday the earth shook and grew dark. Frightful storms lashed at the earth.</p>
<p>Those evil men who sought His life rejoiced. Now that Jesus was no more, surely those who followed Him would disperse. On that day they stood triumphant.</p>
<p>On that day the veil of the temple was rent in twain.</p>
<p>Mary Magdalene and Mary, the mother of Jesus, were both overcome with grief and despair. The superb man they had loved and honored hung lifeless upon the cross.</p>
<p>On that Friday the Apostles were devastated. Jesus, their Savior—the man who had walked on water and raised the dead—was Himself at the mercy of wicked men. They watched helplessly as He was overcome by His enemies.</p>
<p>On that Friday the Savior of mankind was humiliated and bruised, abused and reviled.</p>
<p>It was a Friday filled with devastating, consuming sorrow that gnawed at the souls of those who loved and honored the Son of God.</p>
<p>I think that of all the days since the beginning of this world’s history, that Friday was the darkest.</p>
<p>But the doom of that day did not endure.</p>
<p>The despair did not linger because on Sunday, the resurrected Lord burst the bonds of death. He ascended from the grave and appeared gloriously triumphant as the Savior of all mankind.</p>
<p>And in an instant the eyes that had been filled with ever-flowing tears dried. The lips that had whispered prayers of distress and grief now filled the air with wondrous praise, for Jesus the Christ, the Son of the living God, stood before them as the first fruits of the Resurrection, the proof that death is merely the beginning of a new and wondrous existence.</p>
<p>Each of us will have our own Fridays—those days when the universe itself seems shattered and the shards of our world lie littered about us in pieces. We all will experience those broken times when it seems we can never be put together again. We will all have our Fridays.</p>
<p>But I testify to you in the name of the One who conquered death—Sunday will come. In the darkness of our sorrow, Sunday will come.</p>
<p>No matter our desperation, no matter our grief, Sunday will come. In this life or the next, Sunday will come.”</p>
<hr>
<p>My hope is that as Spencer passed through the veil, he could he could hear the words of Paul in his mind.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>The time in my departure is at hand. I have fought a good fight. I have finished my course. I have kept the faith.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>May we all remember our dear friend Spencer and the compass that he used to guide his life, the Savior, Jesus Christ.</p>
<p>May we take the example that Spencer set for us and following the Savior that we may invite the Savior more fully into our lives and willingly give our shortcomings to him that he may help us be perfect in Him.</p>
<p>My testimony is that Sunday will come that glorious day when we will be reunited with those we love and rejoice in the great gift that the Savior has given us through his sacrifice in the name of Jesus Christ, Amen.</p>
<hr>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230930 The Funeral/distant_mtn.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="steven-irvine" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="steven-irvine">Steven Irvine</h2>
<p>Spencer was a special person.</p>
<p>As you heard from Kristy, he was the most Christ like.</p>
<p>Kind, caring, loving person that I know.</p>
<p>He was the best older brother. He was the best friend. And the best example, that I could have.</p>
<p>This week has been a week of reflection for me</p>
<p>I tried to figure out and appreciate how much my life was influenced by my older brother and the 31 years that I was able to spend with him.</p>
<p>I realized I attribute so much of who I am to who he was And how much I wanted to be like him.</p>
<p>Growing up, I shared a room with him and we always talked before going to bed in our little bunk beds.</p>
<p>All of my hobbies, all of my knowledge came from his influence. And because he loved history and civil war, so I know about Antietam and Gettysburg Because he was so obsessed with those things and we’d go on these trips over to Virginia and have fun as a family.</p>
<p>Because that’s what Spencer loved. I just wanted to be there with him and I wanted to learn about these that he loved.</p>
<p>My love for all sports comes from his nerdiness.</p>
<p>All thosee stats that he knew and I’m going to miss texting</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>hey, what do you think about this guy</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And he would text me back all these stats.</p>
<p>That’s just who he was.</p>
<p>He was so loving and knowledgeable. He just gave everything his all, I always wanted to follow in his footsteps.</p>
<p>I wanted to be the college football fan that could talk football with my brother. I wanted to play the video games, growing up with my brother and my sister, and have fun playing Mario Kart with them.</p>
<p>I just wanted to be him.</p>
<p>That’s what what I’ve realized over this last week. I really wanted to be my brother.</p>
<p>Because he just set such a good example for me.</p>
<p>How to be man How to be an adult. How to be a spouse.</p>
<p>Because he adored Meg and he treated her like a queen. And I thought to myself one day I want to love somebody like that because I saw how much he loved her.</p>
<p>He was everything I could ask for from an older brother. He was truly the best example. He had the best laugh, even though it was a little too loud.</p>
<p>We all loved it.</p>
<p>You can read all the hundreds of Facebook comments about him and his contagious laughter, with his big smile and how it just came out of his chest.</p>
<p>And you knew exactly where he was at all times.</p>
<p>He had so much fun with everything that he did and he just loved life so much.</p>
<p>And there’s a word that I was thinking of. How do I how do I explain who Spencer was? To somebody who didn’t know my older brother.</p>
<p>The word is <code>Vigor</code>. And that’s just how Spencer lived.</p>
<p>He lived with so much vigor, he loved life, he loved everybody.</p>
<p>He was everybody’s best friend. He talked to people on the airplane. Who does that? But that was Spencer.</p>
<p>He was everybody’s best friend. He always had a smile on his face.</p>
<p>If you look at any of those pictures, you knew he was a happy person. And he was so Christ like.</p>
<p>He was so loving. He was so caring. And it’s just as my sister said. He leaves such a big hole in our family.</p>
<p>And now, as I try to compare myself to him,</p>
<p>He would call my parents out of the blue to check up on them.</p>
<p>I call my parents to get something from them, or ask them a question. But Spencer cared about how my dad’s day was going. While I was like,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>oh, I could call my dad today, I guess, but…</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He just he loved them so much and he was just such a good son.</p>
<p>He was my dad’s best friend. He always thought about them. He always thought about other people, even when he was sick last Wednesday.</p>
<p>Out of the blue, he called me – four times. I thought this was strange.</p>
<p>I was working and I missed the calls. I thought it was weird that he called me four times and he left me a voicemail.</p>
<p>And the voicemail starts off with.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Love you little bro. Thank you so much for praying for us and all the support.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And then he ends it with</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>love you so much. Take care, Steven.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And I didn’t at the time, I didn’t think much of it Because well, we will have time with him. But, why did he call me? On a Wednesday during a work day.</p>
<p>Why did he feel like he had to call me so many times and I ended up calling him back and we had a really great chat for 45 minutes.</p>
<p>That was the last time I spoke to him.</p>
<p>But he knew somehow that he needed to leave me this message that I’m going to cherish for the rest of my life.</p>
<p>He knew that he needed to call me then because he wasn’t going to have an opportunity again.</p>
<p>He knew that he just needed to talk to me. Somehow some way Spencer knew.</p>
<p>Despite feeling low, despite being bloated and having pain and being on painkillers. Knowing that there was a very grim prognosis for him, he called me in the middle of the week, last Wednesday.</p>
<p>To tell me that he loved me.</p>
<p>Because that’s just who he was.</p>
<p>I couldn’t imagine my life without him.</p>
<p>No matter what I did, he was always the prouder, older brother.</p>
<p>Even when he was unemployed and struggling and really challenged. I got a job and I started moving up the ladder and he was always so proud of me.</p>
<p>And looking back</p>
<p>If I were in his shoes, I’d be thinking,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>what a little punk. Why does he get a job. How is he doing this and I’m not? I have the master’s degree.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>There would be so many things going through my mind of how I would have reacted to these negative situations.</p>
<p>But Spencer didn’t.</p>
<p>Every time I texted him, he was always so proud of me. He was always so happy for me.</p>
<p>I don’t know how I would have reacted to all that. I don’t know how I would have been non judgmental. Or not angry? At all of these circumstances that happened to me.</p>
<p>But no matter what, he was just such a trooper. He was always so positive in the middle of all. Whether his diagnosis or Doctor visits, he would call me and tell me.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>You know what? I’m going to beat this thing. I’m going to stay positive. I’m going to do it. And we’re going to beat it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He had so much hope. And so much love.</p>
<p>I remember one of the last things he told me on that Wednesday.</p>
<p>How amazing our family has been for him. How much support his friends and family have given him all across the world. How amazing his wife was for doing everything for him, taking him to the ER all those times and bearing that burden with him.</p>
<p>As I look throughout the years and I think of how amazing of an older brother he was.</p>
<p>Every situation that I would have reacted negatively, he reacted positively.</p>
<p>Every person that he met, he left with a good impression When I probably would have been judgmental.</p>
<p>He was a better man.</p>
<p>He was so positive. So Christ like So loving.</p>
<p>He set a good example for me, despite everything that he faced. He was always encouraging me, always trying to teach me and be the supportive older brother that he knew that he needed to be.</p>
<p>And last Saturday, before we came down to Arizona on Sunday, for the first time in years, I watched college football in our basement.</p>
<p>I said to myself,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Wow, this would be really fun if Spencer gets his chemo treatment and he feels good enough, one day I’ll fly him up here so we can have another college football Saturday that we used to have growing up.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I felt a little bit of Spencer next to me. Looking back at it, it feels very surreal that I almost felt like I had him with me. For that one day, the day before he passed, I decided to watch college football. That I decided to do that one thing that he loves so much doing with me.</p>
<p>And I felt him and that a little part of him was there with me I will cherish that moment for the rest of my life.</p>
<p>I love my brother so much.</p>
<p>He’s such a good example to me. He was the most Christlike person that I know. And I will miss him dearly.</p>
<p>And I want to close this with my testimony. I know that I’m going to see him again. And I can’t wait to see him and get one of those big bear hugs that he always gives.</p>
<p>Because I’m already missing those.</p>
<p>I know that he’s watching over us. And I know that the plan of salvation is real and I can’t wait to see him again.</p>
<p>I say that in the name of Jesus Christ.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230930 The Funeral/fall2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="alfredo-lopez" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="alfredo-lopez">Alfredo Lopez</h2>
<p>Good morning. My name is Alfredo and like all of you, I had the privilege of calling Spencer, my friend.</p>
<p>I want to give a tribute to Spencer and tell you all the amazing adventures that we went on.</p>
<p>I really don’t remember my life Without Spencer.</p>
<p>When my family moved to the United States from Lima, Peru. Spencer was literally one of my first friends.</p>
<p>So I literally don’t remember much at all the adventures we’ve been on while Spencer being there with me, - or me calling him, - or reaching out to him, - or sending him pictures, - or him sending me pictures back, - or something awesome that we were doing.</p>
<hr>
<p>We we went to middle school together. We went to Argon Middle school. And we have a social studies class together.</p>
<p>And I was still learning English. And island is spelled ISLAND, right?</p>
<p>The S is silent. So you say island. And I was in the class and I said Iceland because I pronounce the S because in Spanish you pronounce all the letters.</p>
<p>Spencer was like.</p>
<p>No, no, don’t say it like that,</p>
<p>I’m like, why not? Are you sure that doesn’t sound right?</p>
<p>But and then I told the teacher, I asked her about the Iceland. And she said, we’re talking about Islands</p>
<p>I was like, Oh.</p>
<p>That was my relationship with Spencer.</p>
<hr>
<p>I called Spencer my personal political adviser.</p>
<p>Whenever I needed something or I needed to know something.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>What’s going on?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I always call Spencer or text him.</p>
<p>I’ll say,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Hey Spencer. What is going on with this cause? He already knew about it, had done all the research on it and so he gave me all the information.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He gave me the Cliff notes as well. And it was amazing.</p>
<p>Spencer was also my mentor – always.</p>
<hr>
<p>I was conflicted whether or not to wear my service uniform today. But I’m wearing it, to honor Spencer.</p>
<p>10 years ago I enlist in the Marine Corps. I now serve in the army. When I was going through the process of which branch to join, who do you think I was calling?</p>
<p>I was calling Spencer. Because he knew all about the branches and what was going on with each one of them.</p>
<p>So when I went to see the Air Force recruiters, right after that, I called Spencer.</p>
<p>When I went to see the Navy recruiters, then I called Spencer.</p>
<p>But not with the Army recruitors, since I didn’t want anything to do with the army.</p>
<p>But here I am.</p>
<p>And then, I went to see the Marines recruiters, and I called Spencer.</p>
<p>He was like,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>yeah, you should do that one I think would be great.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And it was terrible. It really was.</p>
<p>The training was horrible.</p>
<p>But I stuck through it. And when I graduated, the recruit training in San Diego. I called Spencer.</p>
<p>I said, hey, man, I did it because of you</p>
<hr>
<p>Spencer and I, we grew up in what I now I’m calling <code>The Fabulous 5</code>.</p>
<p>Our fearless leader, our Captain Moroni, was Spencer.</p>
<p>He was our righteous leader.</p>
<p>From the moment we were deacons, he was a deacons president. And we knew that we had to follow Spencer because he was always ready to do the right thing no matter what it was. And he motivated us all to do it.</p>
<p>Part of this gang was also Danny B., Michael S., Brandon R. and myself. Now the five of us we grew up together since we were 12, all he way to our missions and then we moved on with our lives</p>
<p>But during these formative years and our teenage years, looking back, Spencer was our rock.</p>
<p>He was so diligent, so smart.</p>
<p>I was talking to Michael and he told me that he wanted to be a student like Spencer.</p>
<p>So he started meet up with Spencer to do his homework together because Spencer was a very serious student.</p>
<p>One thing about Spencer was his dilligence, he was amazing, I admire him for that.</p>
<p>But then Michael started to kind of corrupt Spencer.</p>
<p>He would say,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>hey, Spencer instead of doing homework, what if we played on the Xbox. Let’s go play some Battlefront</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And Spencer would respond,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>No, we gotta do homework, man.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>But Spencer was so nice, so he would crack down a few times. But then he was like, no, this isn’t right.</p>
<p>We’re not doing this.</p>
<hr>
<p>Spencer wasa really kind person and absolutely amazing.</p>
<p>But on the sports field he had no mercy.</p>
<p>I hated to play against him any sport, whether it was soccer, football, basketball.</p>
<p>Because as sweet as Spencer is.</p>
<p>Oh my goodness. On the sports field he became a warrior.</p>
<p>I ran so fast as to not get tackled by him.</p>
<p>For every Turkey Bowl, I always make sure I was on Spencer team. Because I didn’t want him chasing me down.</p>
<p>And it was awesome to see when he joined the high school football team. He loved it and it was great.</p>
<p>And I was so glad he was there because he was so tough.</p>
<p>I like to consider myself tough, but no Spencer is tough, so much tougher than me.</p>
<hr>
<p>Then Spencer served mission in California and he learned that language <code>de los ceielos</code></p>
<p>The tongue of the heavens.</p>
<p>And when he came back and we met up after our missions.</p>
<p>It was a brand new world of our friendship, because now I still got Spencer, but we could also talk to the senoritas.</p>
<p>I would say,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>let’s go down some machaca and salsa,</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And Spencer was always down.</p>
<p>He was like,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>OK, let’s go.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So, Spencer, we’re gonna be coming home at 6:00 in the morning.</p>
<p>He would say,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Alright, let’s do it.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>You know, we took care of each other.</p>
<hr>
<p>It was so beautiful to see how he now could communicate with my parents in a whole different way.</p>
<p>Growing up with Spencer and the Irvines, they were our families as well.</p>
<p>And Spencer was so excited, I could see that excitement in his face when he first talked to my mom in Spanish.</p>
<p>And his Spanish was amazing. You know, it was LA Spanish, which, we forgave him for that. But it was still amazing.</p>
<p>And he would come and ask my mom for the recipes for Arroz con pollo and Huancaina, which are some Peruvian dishes, and he loved them.</p>
<p>Spencer was always at the weddings of my family He was there when my sister got married. Also when I got married.</p>
<p>It was just awesome.</p>
<p>Because Spencer was my rock. He was also full of love. And so humble.</p>
<hr>
<p>This was during one of our many, many camping trips with the scouts.</p>
<p>For some reason I didn’t have any warm gear and I was freezing.</p>
<p>Spencer noticed that</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Hey man, here, take my coat.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I was like,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>no, no, you’re gonna need it because it was really cold.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I think we were in mountains in western Maryland, Sugarloaf Mountains, and we spent all night trading the coat because I was freezing and he was freezing</p>
<p>But you know, we got some sleep.</p>
<p>He took care of me and I tried to take care of him.</p>
<p>Since then, we grew into our 30s and moved on with our lives.</p>
<p>I would, from time to time, would still check in with Spencer.</p>
<hr>
<p>In the fall of 2021, I got assigned to be deployed to Eastern Europe for a year.</p>
<p>It said on my assignment, Kosovo and I was like, where is that?</p>
<p>So I made three phone calls.</p>
<p>The first one was my wife,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I’m getting deployed. I’m leaving for a little bit.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Then my parents, to let them know.</p>
<p>Then Spencer, I was like,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Spencer, what do you know about this place?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>and he already knew all about it.</p>
<p>And I was like,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Amazing.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He was my Intel guy to the Intel officer.</p>
<p>It was awesome, and even when I was gone, I would ask,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>hey, Spencer, what’s going on here</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He would respond,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>let me. Look up. I’ll get back to you.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So now, I don’t have that Intel guy anymore.</p>
<p>For now.</p>
<p>Because I know I will see him again.</p>
<hr>
<p>Last Friday, my brother texted me and said,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>hey, I think Spencer is sick.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I said,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>oh, let me hit him up, see what’s going on.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So last Saturday I called him.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Hey, Spencer, I heard you aren’t feeling well.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And he filled me in</p>
<p>And I told Spencer.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>You have to beat this thing.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Because he had to meet my son, Levi Lopez. He was born 3 weeks ago.</p>
<p>Spencer said,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>YES ~ I’m going to do this.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>As Kristy and Steven said, Spencer was extremely positive.</p>
<p>The most positive person I’ve met.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>’Cause I’m gonna beat this thing and overcome.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And I said, perfect.</p>
<p>When you come back out to Maryland, I’m gonna kidnap you. Gonna go down to Virginia. We’re gonna hang out in the Potomac.</p>
<p>It’s gonna be amazing.</p>
<p>He will meet my children. And we will go… We will go on many more adventures.</p>
<p>Because that is what the gospel is all about.</p>
<p>It’s eternal relationships.</p>
<hr>
<p>Friends are like seasons.</p>
<p>Some come and go, but not Spencer.</p>
<p>He was my rock.</p>
<p>This restored gospel is True. And I love it with all my heart. My testimony was stronger.</p>
<p>Because of Spencer.</p>
<hr>
<p>I remember the joy in his face when he opened his mission call.</p>
<p>He was going to learn Spanish, he was so pumped about that.</p>
<p>I look forward to seeing my friend again. He is my brother.</p>
<p>Because I know I will because Christ came to the earth and he atoned for our sins. And He knew that Spencer was a faithful disciple of Jesus Christ.</p>
<p>He never wavered. He was one of the best examples for me.</p>
<hr>
<p>I called my dad and asked him how I should organized some of my thoughts today.</p>
<p>He replied with this.</p>
<p>You can cry because he’s gone. Or</p>
<p>You can smile because of the amazing life that he lived.</p>
<p>You can close your eyes and pray that he will come back right now. Or</p>
<p>You could open your eyes and look at everything that he did that he left behind.</p>
<p>Your heart is void because he’s not here anymore. Or it could be full of joy because the good times you had with him.</p>
<p>You could cry. You could close your mind and feel the emptiness and turn around.</p>
<p>Or you could do what he would have wanted you to do.</p>
<p>Which is to smile. Open your eyes and love. And endure to the end.</p>
<hr>
<p>And so that’s what I’m going to do. I’m going to smile and honor my friend.</p>
<p>And remember all the great times we had.</p>
<p>I’m going to love. I’m going to talk to people on airplanes.</p>
<p>I’m going to be more attentive.</p>
<p>I’m going to love deeply.</p>
<p>Because that’s what Spencer did. That is what I’m going to do — `till the end.</p>
<p>Because the only explanation that I have is this, that Heavenly Father needed Spencer. By His side.</p>
<p>Because that is how amazing he is. So I have to get there too</p>
<p>I have to live this gospel and under the eternal covenants that we have with Heavenly Father.</p>
<hr>
<p>I’m so grateful to have the privilege to have spent my life with him. And for him to be my friend and my brother.</p>
<p>My family loves me so deeply.</p>
<p>Every single one of my siblings. There are six of us in total. We all have unique experiences with Spencer.</p>
<p>We all love him so much.</p>
<p>There isn’t a picture from our teenage years that are without Spencer in it.</p>
<p>I know that this gospel is true. The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter Day Saints is the only true church on this earth.</p>
<p>Spencer knew it too.</p>
<p>And he shared that message with everyone he met in California.</p>
<p>That was his mission.</p>
<p>And so thankful for all of you, and for your support.</p>
<p>And I say all these things. In the name of our savior, Jesus Christ, Amen.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230930 The Funeral/provo_temple.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="bishop-mccormack-2" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="bishop-mccormack-2">Bishop McCormack</h2>
<p>Two favorite songs that all primary children sing.</p>
<p><code>I'm a child of God</code> and <code>Families Can Be Together Forever</code>.</p>
<p>Two basic truths of the gospel.</p>
<p>Thank you to all family and friends for their beautiful messages and music this morning.</p>
<p>The Spirit was felt here in this Chapel.</p>
<p>If I can ask you to please take your hymnal out and turn to the hymn #86 that we sang this morning. (See Section&nbsp;0.2)</p>
<p>This hymn was not written by Emma Smith or one of the members of the past as the majority of songs in this book were.</p>
<p>We adopted this hymn because it brings to the focus, the fundamental plan of happiness, the main theme in the Book of Mormon.</p>
<p>In the first verse, the prominent section gives God, the glory for creating a world where we could come to gain the experience we need to grow up.</p>
<p>We need to grow up to be like our Heavenly Father.</p>
<p>Please turn your attention to the next verse, which brings us to the experience. the wonders of this earth. And the joy within</p>
<p>In Galatians 5:22 and 23 , it reads.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>But the fruit of the Spirit is love, joy, peace, longsuffering, gentleness, goodness, faith, meekness, temperance: against such there is no law.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>That’s what Spencer represented.</p>
<p>We are here to be happy.</p>
<p>Joseph Smith said.</p>
<p>It is the the design of our existence.</p>
<p>Now, as with all things, there needs to be an opposite. If not, we could not grow or have the agency to choose and make decisions for ourselves without depending on others to make them for us.</p>
<p>To be forced without agency is evil, and this is what the adversary wants. And since we are imperfect and expected to be imperfect, our Father’s Plan is to send His Son, His only begotten to redeem us from our imperfection, or save us from our mistakes.</p>
<p>In the third verse is the one that tears at me. It’s the one that when I ponder it, there’s something. There’s someone who loves me so much that would sacrifice Himself to go through such terrible experiences in the Garden of Gethsemane so that he can know my experiences of pain.</p>
<p>Through this act, in which no one understands how it works. He knows what we feel when someone we love without any fault of their own departs from this earth.</p>
<p>As the verse says. <code>I scarce can take it in</code>.</p>
<p>However, brothers and sisters, there’s hope. Meaning, whether we believe it or not, there comes a time when the Savior will return to embrace and congratulate us.</p>
<p>For, as we say in our faith, endure to the end.</p>
<p><code>Then I shall bow in humble adoration</code>. <code>And there proclaim my God</code>. <code>How great thou art</code>.</p>
<p>In 2 Nephi 4, Lehi blesses his posterity and passes away.</p>
<p>In reading Nephi’s words, Nephi seem initially and understandably, to have a difficult time with his father’s passing.</p>
<p>In verse 13, Nephi stated that his brothers, Laman and Lemuel were angry with him.</p>
<p>Can you imagine the scenario of all the trials that Nephi had gone through because of his brothers?</p>
<p>And then on top of all of that, the Lord said,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Don’t Nephi. You are not allowed to say anymore to them.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>For the next few verses, Nephi remembers all that the Lord has done for him.</p>
<p>He remembers this because there was a choice he had to make.</p>
<p>He’s been through many afflictions and remember he’s grieving or mourning his father’s death.</p>
<p>This is what he said in verse 27.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>And why should I yield to sin, because of my flesh? Yea, why should I give way to temptations, that the evil one have place in my heart to destroy my peace and afflict my soul? Why am I angry because of mine enemy?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He’s Speaking of Laman and Lemuel.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Awake, my soul! No longer droop in sin. Rejoice, O my heart, and give place no more for the enemy of my soul.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Do not anger again because of mine enemies. Do not slacken my strength because of mine afflictions.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I ask you to please read the last five verses of the end of Nephi Chapter 4. Nephi pulls himself together and teaches us how to turn to the Lord to help in times of affliction.</p>
<p>These verses are very personal to him. And if you think of how he’s feeling when he writes these verses. There’s a parallel here with Nephi.</p>
<p>During a very vulnerable time for him after losing his father. And with all of us grieving the loss of Spencer.</p>
<p>In my opinion, Nephi’s personal struggle and passion is more apparent in these verses than in any other of his writings.</p>
<p>In verse 30, it begins with this with this prayer and pleas. I ask you to put yourself in his place. And repeat this prayer in your mind. And Nephi asks that you pray unto the Lord in this manner.</p>
<p>In verse 30.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>O Lord, I will praise thee forever; yea, my soul will rejoice in thee, my God, and the rock of my salvation.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>O Lord, wilt thou redeem my soul? Wilt thou deliver me out of the hands of mine enemies? Wilt thou make me that I may shake at the appearance of sin?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He continues, in verse 33</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>O Lord, wilt thou encircle me around in the robe of thy righteousness! O Lord, wilt thou make a way for mine escape before mine enemies! Wilt thou make my path straight before me! Wilt thou not place a stumbling block in my way—but that thou wouldst clear my way before me, and hedge not up my way, but the ways of mine enemy.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>O Lord, I have trusted in thee, and I will trust in thee forever. I will not put my trust in the arm of flesh; for I know that cursed is he that putteth his trust in the arm of flesh. Yea, cursed is he that putteth his trust in man or maketh flesh his arm.</p>
</blockquote>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Yea, I know that God will give liberally to him that asketh. Yea, my God will give me, if I bask cnot amiss; therefore I will lift up my voice unto thee; yea, I will cry unto thee, my God, the drock of my erighteousness. Behold, my voice shall forever ascend up unto thee, my rock and mine everlasting God. Amen.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I would like to bear in my testimony that I know God lives. He loves us. He sent his Son to redeem us.</p>
<p>I know that Joseph Smith is a prophet of God And he translated the Book of Mormon by the power of God.</p>
<p>I know that the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints is the church here on this earth today</p>
<p>And I know that this church is led by a prophet, a living prophet, who receives revelation</p>
<p>Thank you all for being here.</p>
<p>Meg, We love you.</p>
<p>We love your family. Although for a short time, I know that they love you. You have such great support. And it goes without saying that Spencer was such a great guy.</p>
<p>I leave you with a blessing that you will always stay close to the gospel. He’s smiling down and up on us right now.</p>
<p>I know who he is.</p>
<p>And I say these things, in the name of Jesus Christ, Amen.</p>
</section>
<section id="closing-prayer---elijah-nunez" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="closing-prayer---elijah-nunez">Closing Prayer - Elijah Nunez</h2>
<p>Our dear Heavenly Father. We thank thee for this day that thou hast blessed us with.</p>
<p>For the time that we have now to say goodbye to Spencer in this life. We’re grateful for many years and the time that thou hast blessed us to be with him in this life. And to know him, to love him.</p>
<p>We thank thee for this gospel and for the plan of salvation. We’re grateful for the promise of being able to live and be with our loved ones again.</p>
<p>We ask thee to please bless us this time as we say goodbye. So that we continue to remember, Spencer.</p>
<p>That we’ll be looking for opportunities in our life to love and serve the people around us.</p>
<p>With happiness and kindness.</p>
<p>We asked thee to please continue to bless us all. T0 continue to have the Spirit with us. Help us, to do our best, as we live in this life.</p>
<p>We love thee and say these things in the name of Jesus Christ, Amen.</p>
<script src="https://utteranc.es/client.js" repo="https://github.com/spencerirvinereed/blogComment" issue-term="pathname" theme="github-light" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>


</section>
</section>


<div id="quarto-appendix" class="default"><section id="footnotes" class="footnotes footnotes-end-of-document"><h2 class="anchored quarto-appendix-heading">Footnotes</h2>

<ol>
<li id="fn1"><p>https://hymnary.org/hymn/LDS1985/86↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn2"><p>https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/music/library/hymns/families-can-be-together-forever?lang=eng↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn3"><p>https://www.austincc.edu/dlauderb/1302/Lyrics/BattleHymnoftheRepublic.htm↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn4"><p><a href="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/general-conference/2018/04/pure-love-the-true-sign-of-every-true-disciple-of-jesus-christ?lang=eng">link</a>↩︎</p></li>
<li id="fn5"><p><a href="https://www.churchofjesuschrist.org/study/general-conference/2006/10/sunday-will-come?lang=eng">link</a>↩︎</p></li>
</ol>
</section></div> ]]></description>
  <category>recording</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230930 The Funeral/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230930 The Funeral/sunrise2.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Spencer : The College Man</title>
  <dc:creator>Mark Nielsen</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I’ll always treasure Spencer’s friendship and all the incredible times we had in college as roommates.&nbsp; He will be missed and we are praying for you!&nbsp; Love you guys!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Photos and Memories of Spencer taken by his roommates, <code>Mark Nielsen</code>, <code>Kameron Welsch</code>, and <code>Jacob Molnar</code>.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/DSCN4195.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Below are some of Mark’s memories of Spencer when they lived together in the Marin Apartments in South Provo from August 2010 thru April 2011.</p>
<section id="memories-of-spencer" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="memories-of-spencer">Memories of Spencer</h2>
<p>I can’t remember how many times I came back to the apartment feeling tense or stressed because of school or work, but Spencer knew just how to get me laughing which broke the tension I was feeling.</p>
<p>When things were getting more serious between Michelle and I, Michelle asked for some time to consider the next step in our relationship…</p>
<p>That was the longest day and a half in my life!&nbsp;</p>
<p>Spencer, realizing that something was up,asked how things were.&nbsp; He never pressured me to share details of what was going on, but just listened.&nbsp;</p>
<p>I asked him for a blessing and he gave me a wonderful blessing that brought me comfort and peace.&nbsp; That’s when I realized what a true friend Spencer was to me.</p>
<p>Shortly after this, Spencer helped me set up a scavenger hunt for me to be able to propose to Michelle.&nbsp; He sat next to the BYU duck pond, waiting for Michelle to covertly make an “exchange” of briefcases as he read a newspaper.&nbsp; Then he rushed multiple additional clues to significant locations for Michelle and I.&nbsp; He was an incredible friend and sacrificed so much!</p>
<p>While on multiple trips to do some work training in the Maryland/DC.&nbsp; Spencer was excited and always willing to meet up at Chili’s or Buffalo Wild Wings to just hang out and chat.&nbsp; Was so nice to see a friendly face so far away from home!</p>
<p>On Halloween, Spencer dressed up as a mime and despite our many efforts to get him to break character and talk, he never did once… although we did get him to laugh once or twice.</p>
</section>
<section id="photos-of-spencer" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="photos-of-spencer">Photos of Spencer</h2>
<section id="playground-group-date-2010-09" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="playground-group-date-2010-09">Playground Group Date 2010-09</h3>
<div class="quarto-layout-panel">
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/DSCN4223.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Hopscotch</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/DSCN4263.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">The Sign</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/DSCN4260.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Playground</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/DSCN4230.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Hopscotch 2</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
<section id="cookie-delivery---2010-11" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="cookie-delivery---2010-11">Cookie Delivery - 2010-11</h3>
<div class="quarto-layout-panel">
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/Picnic!!! 006.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Picnic 1</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/Picnic!!! 004.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Picnic 2</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/Picnic!!! 005.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Picnic 3</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/Kameron 314.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Kameron</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</section>
</section>
<section id="college-days" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="college-days">2012 College Days</h2>
<div class="quarto-layout-panel">
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/DSCF0015.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/DSCF0116.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/DSCF0111.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/DSCF0124.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-panel">
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/DSCF0121.JPG" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/img_1_1696014935358.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/img_3_1696014979788.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/img_4_1696014996716.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-panel">
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/img_6_1696015032557.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/img_27_1696018822283.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/img_7_1696015044695.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/img_21_1696018620360.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</div>
</div>
</div>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/img_24_1696018712821.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="journal-entries-about-spencer" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="journal-entries-about-spencer">Journal entries about Spencer</h2>
<section id="april-2010" class="level3">
<h3 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="april-2010">27 April 2010 –</h3>
<p>Well – we just decided on a place to live!&nbsp; We will be in the Marin apartments… with Spencer and Kameron! Wahoo!</p>
</section>
</section>
<section id="sept.-2010" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sept.-2010">23 Sept.&nbsp;2010 –</h2>
<p>Spencer just gave the most wonderful and sincere prayer I have ever heard in my entire life. He is such a good friend and a great man.&nbsp; I love him for his strength and his faith in me.&nbsp; He prayed/plead for each of us (Me, Kameron, and Mike) and thanked Heavenly Father for us.&nbsp; I’ll never forget how I felt.</p>
</section>
<section id="oct.-2010" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="oct.-2010">10 Oct.&nbsp;2010 –</h2>
<p>[After church] my friends and roomies played Phase 10 together.&nbsp; In memory of 10/10/10.</p>
</section>
<section id="feb-2011" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="feb-2011">18 Feb 2011 –</h2>
<p>I am ENGAGED!&nbsp; So… first I met Michell at her place. I had given her four gifts, each with… a clue.&nbsp; She figured it out and the place to go was my apartment. Then the scavenger hunt started… Spencer Irvine helped me by giving her the “mission, if she chose to accept it”, by being at “drop points” and taking stuff where I needed it…</p>
<hr>
<script src="https://utteranc.es/client.js" repo="https://github.com/spencerirvinereed/blogComment" issue-term="pathname" theme="github-light" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>remembering</category>
  <category>friendship</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Mark_Nielsen_Tribute/DSCN4195.JPG" medium="image"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Working Years - 2013 - 2017</title>
  <dc:creator>Irvine Family</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Working Years - 2013 - 2017/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="snowman" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="snowman">Snowman</h2>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Working Years - 2013 - 2017/snow_shovel.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="sports-fan" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="sports-fan">Sports Fan</h2>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Working Years - 2013 - 2017/NLDS.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Working Years - 2013 - 2017/rover.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">20170430, Gaithursburg, MD</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</section>
<section id="car-show" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="car-show">Car Show</h2>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Working Years - 2013 - 2017/car_show1.jpeg" class="img-fluid"> <img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Working Years - 2013 - 2017/car_show2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"> <img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Working Years - 2013 - 2017/car_show3.jpeg" class="img-fluid"> <img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Working Years - 2013 - 2017/car_show4.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Working Years - 2013 - 2017/friends.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Working Years - 2013 - 2017/game.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Working Years - 2013 - 2017/game2.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>blog</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Working Years - 2013 - 2017/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Working Years - 2013 - 2017/snow_shovel.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>BYU Years - 2007 - 2012</title>
  <dc:creator>Irvine Family</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/BYU Years - 2007 - 2012/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="alfredo-lopezs-recollection" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="alfredo-lopezs-recollection">Alfredo Lopez’s Recollection</h2>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/BYU Years - 2007 - 2012/nice_shot.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/BYU Years - 2007 - 2012/college_life1.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Collge Friends</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/BYU Years - 2007 - 2012/holi_festival.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Colors Festival, Spanish Fork"> <img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/BYU Years - 2007 - 2012/temple_marriage.jpg" class="img-fluid" alt="Temple Marriage"></p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/BYU Years - 2007 - 2012/tux_group.jpg" class="img-fluid"> <img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/BYU Years - 2007 - 2012/tux_kid.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>blog</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/BYU Years - 2007 - 2012/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/BYU Years - 2007 - 2012/nice_shot.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>California Mission - 2007-2009</title>
  <dc:creator>Elder Irvine</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/California Mission - 2007 - 2009/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="letter-home-10-december-2007" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="letter-home-10-december-2007">Letter Home, 10 December 2007</h2>
</section>
<section id="letter-home-19-november-2007" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="letter-home-19-november-2007">Letter Home, 19 November 2007</h2>
</section>
<section id="letter-home-24-march-2008" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="letter-home-24-march-2008">Letter Home, 24 March 2008</h2>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>letters</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/California Mission - 2007 - 2009/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/California Mission - 2007 - 2009/IMG_2180.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Teenage Years - 2000 - 2007</title>
  <dc:creator>Irvine Family</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Teenage Years - 2000 - 2007/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<section id="alfredo-lopezs-memories" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="alfredo-lopezs-memories">Alfredo Lopez’s Memories</h2>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Teenage Years - 2000 - 2007/alfredo_spencer.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">High School?</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Teenage Years - 2000 - 2007/by_garage.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="alicia-hilton" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="alicia-hilton">Alicia Hilton</h2>
<p>Spencer Irvine was incredibly sweet, kind, smart and funny.</p>
<p>We spent 3 years together in early morning seminary and he was still all of those things at 6am!</p>
<p>I can still hear his great laugh and I will never forget him as Mr.&nbsp;Mumbles in the road show!</p>
<p>Sending all my love and prayers to the Irvine family during this time.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Teenage Years - 2000 - 2007/road_show.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="ashley-jane" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="ashley-jane">Ashley Jane</h2>
<p>The pic says it all: Spencer could light up a room (mostly because he was hilarious). Losing him hurts…Real bad. Sending love and prayers to the Irvine family.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Teenage Years - 2000 - 2007/ashley.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="christopher-gill" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="christopher-gill">Christopher Gill</h2>
<p>Spencer thank you for being such a great friend. I remember how kind you were to me and my mom when we first moved into Derwood Ward. All the great times we spent at camp outs, youth activities and just hanging out together as friends. You will be missed my Brother. May you rest in peace in Heaven.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Teenage Years - 2000 - 2007/chris_gill.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
</section>
<section id="megan-beth-lott" class="level2">
<h2 class="anchored" data-anchor-id="megan-beth-lott">Megan Beth Lott</h2>
<p>Spencer Irvine was such a happy soul and a pure Joy to work with … he made our world a better and brighter place and will be missed LOTTS!!</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Teenage Years - 2000 - 2007/megan_lott1.jpg" class="img-fluid"><br>
<img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Teenage Years - 2000 - 2007/megan_lott2.jpg" class="img-fluid"><br>
<img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Teenage Years - 2000 - 2007/megan_lott3.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>


</section>

 ]]></description>
  <category>blog</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Teenage Years - 2000 - 2007/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Wed, 27 Sep 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Teenage Years - 2000 - 2007/image.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Our Spencer</title>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230925 SRI Personal/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Our beloved husband, son, brother, and uncle Spencer Reed Irvine, passed away peacefully on the evening of 24 September 2023 in Scottsdale, Arizona after a courageous bout with cancer.</p>
<p>Spencer was born on February 13, 1988 in Rockville, Maryland.</p>
<p>He excelled in all areas of endeavors in life, yet he was humble and a friend to all.<br>
He embodied a gentle kindness to all and was a source of many excellent conversations.</p>
<p>He graduated from Brigham Young University, with an International Relations degree.<br>
He obtained a Master of Public Administration from George Washington University.<br>
He served in the California San Fernando Mission for the Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230925 SRI Personal/temple_cloud.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>His hobbies and enjoyment included history, sport analytics, writing in areas of policies and politics, these shaped his life.</p>
<p>His talent for writing came from an accurate assessment of himself, grounded in his faith in Jesus Christ, and his surroundings.</p>
<p>Often drawing and building upon an initial assessment then rigorously testing his thesis and rewriting as many times as necessary to satisfy his high standard.</p>
<p>Perhaps he gained this skill through his father, Don, and also his grandfather Reed.<br>
Both of whom adored Spencer and influenced his outlook and shaped his core.</p>
<p>From his mother, Young Kang Irvine, Spencer learned hard work and perseverance – a first generation Korean immigrant.</p>
<p>Spencer had great interest in the service of Grandpa Kang in the Korean War and had researched into the battles that Grandpa was involved in.</p>
<p>Whether the setting was academic, religion, or work, Spencer applied all his faculties and energy.</p>
<p>And most responded because they all felt his sincerity and love, which Spencer was blessed with in abundance.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230925 SRI Personal/tree_love.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Many select and establish their North Star and an internal compass, and means to reckon and keep track of passage of time to guide their journey in this life.</p>
<p>Spencer was gifted with an absolute and abiding True North and built himself a never deviating compass, and fashioned a perpetual time keeping method – all based on his faith in Jesus Christ, an understanding of the Will of the Father, and immense love for his fellow travelers.</p>
<p>He knew the purpose of this life, to love others as they need to be loved, without pre-condition or judgment.</p>
<p>Forever grateful that we got to know him and feel his love, taking a part in this journey together.</p>
<p>We have lost a guide, and the pain persists.</p>
<p>He was a leader that showed how to comfort and heal one another.</p>
<p>Spencer is survived by his love of life Meg Nuñez Irvine, loving parents Don and Young, siblings Kristy (Tyler) and Steven (Bree).</p>
<p>The funeral services will be held on Saturday, September 30, 2023, 10AM.<br>
(Viewing will be from 9AM to 9:45AM)</p>
<p>The Church of Jesus Christ of Latter-day Saints at 3920 N 44th Pl, Phoenix, AZ 85018. <a href="https://maps.app.goo.gl/EuyryWaA3nHQc2X29">Church Location</a></p>
<hr>
<p>Topic: Funeral Time: Sep 30, 2023 10:00 AM Arizona</p>
<p>Join Zoom Meeting https://zoom.us/j/96761893836?pwd=ZWNDSUxzTExjOVNJcThwdFRRS2R6UT09 (https://zoom.us/j/96761893836?pwd=ZWNDSUxzTExjOVNJcThwdFRRS2R6UT09)</p>
<p>Meeting ID: 967 6189 3836</p>
<p>Passcode: 093023</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230925 SRI Personal/clouds.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>



 ]]></description>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230925 SRI Personal/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/20230925 SRI Personal/temple_cloud.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Growing Up Years : 1988 - 2000</title>
  <dc:creator>Irvine Family</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/growing up years - before 2000/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/growing up years - before 2000/19940625_AZ.JPG" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Turley’s Wedding, Mesa AZ, June 1994</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/growing up years - before 2000/scout.jpeg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Date TBD</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-panel">
<div class="quarto-layout-row quarto-layout-valign-top">
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/growing up years - before 2000/spencer_at_5.jpeg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Pre School Days, about 5 yrs old</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
<div class="quarto-layout-cell" style="flex-basis: 50.0%;justify-content: center;">
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/growing up years - before 2000/spencer1.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Perhaps at Age 1, PC Mark Volk</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>



 ]]></description>
  <category>blog</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/growing up years - before 2000/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/growing up years - before 2000/bike.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>A Weekend with Spencer</title>
  <dc:creator>Uncle David</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/A March Weekend/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>My sister in Mesa said,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Irvines are flying in, you should come down.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>When someone in AZ invites, I am on my way.</p>
<p>Especially, if the invitation is before Spring Equinox.</p>
<p>Prior to arriving, told Don that we should watch a spring baseball game.</p>
<p>He and Spencer made arrangements.</p>
<p>And just like that we were at the Diablo Stadium. Watching the <code>Texas Rangers</code> play the <code>LA (California) Angels</code></p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/A March Weekend/pano.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">The Buttes, Tempe AZ, May 2016</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>What a venue for a baseball game, or any event.<br>
I had visited this complex during my traveling days.<br>
I wanted to watch a game in person,</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/A March Weekend/baseball_image.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>We were like foreigners following their teams. Traveling abroad to watch them play – even if it a spring practice game.</p>
<p>But it wasn’t the game that entertained and enlightened us.</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/A March Weekend/at_game.jpg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Angels Baseball, 18 March 2023</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<p>For we had a personal baseball commentator, a historian, and the current event interpreter sitting with us.</p>
<p>Spencer had us relaxed, think about ourselves and in turn think about life.</p>
<p>While sitting in an open stadium, feeling the sun with bit of clouds on an early desert spring afternoon.</p>
<p>There was no need for a preparation, just be there and enjoy the conversation.</p>
<p>Thank you Don. Thank you Spencer</p>
<div class="quarto-figure quarto-figure-center">
<figure class="figure">
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/A March Weekend/diablo.jpeg" class="img-fluid figure-img"></p>
<p></p><figcaption class="figure-caption">Diablo Stadium, 18 March 2023</figcaption><p></p>
</figure>
</div>
<script src="https://utteranc.es/client.js" repo="https://github.com/spencerirvinereed/blogComment" issue-term="pathname" theme="github-light" crossorigin="anonymous" async="">
</script>



 ]]></description>
  <category>remembering</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/A March Weekend/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Sat, 18 Mar 2023 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/A March Weekend/pano.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Six Month Mark in Santa Clarita</title>
  <dc:creator>Elder Irvine</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-2/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Dear Family:</p>
<p>I really thought that I ought to have done an April Fool’s number just to keep everyone on their toes.</p>
<p>But, I wouldn’t mind if that happens, but whatever the Lord wants.</p>
<p>It’s hard to keep working when one gets in a routine so I’ve been mixing things up a little bit to keep me balanced and not bored.</p>
<p>Yes, I got the traveler’s checks so I’ll cash it in soon.</p>
<p>And I have so many pictures to send you, but I need the cord to burn it to a CD to send home.</p>
<p>Don’t want a memory swipe to happen again.</p>
<p>And that’s sweet that Steven is improving his grades - I’d love to see him out at BYU!</p>
<p>It’s the best thing to have siblings out at the same college so you’re not too lonely.</p>
<p>This weekend was edifying.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I loved conference.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I missed the main points of Elder Hales’ talk because I fell asleep during his talk and maybe another talk in that session.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>But, it went well for me.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I was really happy to hear Elder Bednar call the members out, because all the members pray for the missionaries but are really passive in helping us with better investigators than we can find their friends!</p>
<p>This conference was really great! I soaked in a lot.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-2/fountain.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Bednar’s was really great, Holland’s wasn’t as argumentative as his last one (I felt energized to go bash after last conference after hearing his talk), and I loved Uchtdorf’s talk in priesthood session.</p>
<p>I learned so much, and the importance of prophets most of all.</p>
<p>Almost (if not) everyone mentioned they sustained the new prophet Thomas S. Monson and testified that the heavens aren’t closed.</p>
<p>I really loved Holland’s talk, how he explained that if we believe in closed canon, we don’t believe God is the same as he was yesterday.</p>
<p>It was a weekend full of being edified by living scriptures. I can’t point out one that I really liked more than the rest.</p>
<p>I am so grateful for a living prophet. It’s sad that people think God doesn’t talk to us anymore.</p>
<p>When I teach, I ask people,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>do you believe God is the same as he was yesterday?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Yes.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>So do you believe that he has always called prophets?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Yes.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>So would you think that he’d call prophets today? He’s the same, right?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>They waffle on this one.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Do we not need God’s help even more today?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>They agree, then try to add something else. But, without a prophet, we are lost. God is really merciful with us.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-2/mtn.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>This week was pretty busy, but relaxed at the end.</p>
<p>A good finish.</p>
<p>At midweeks, we taught 15 lessons, probably one of the best weeks in the mission. I was really happy. We had 4 straight lessons on Tuesday, and that was really tiring!</p>
<p>No matter how hard we try to relax and regain strength each p-day (D&amp;C 10:4 says don’t run faster than you have strength), never works.</p>
<p>We’re tired. Celestial fatigue…</p>
<p>Our ‘golden’ investigator <code>J</code> is a bit questionable. He has quite a temper and is a bit too impatient. He’s been baptized in other churches, and I only found that out talking to his friend <code>R</code> (who’s a member).</p>
<p>We’re going to take our time with him, knowing he’s been baptized in several churches.</p>
<p>It ain’t a game, and I don’t believe he knows that yet.</p>
<p>We’ll see what he really feels when we take our time teaching him. But, he did come to watch conference.</p>
<p>We did have some good news with a woman we’ve been helping clean her house, <code>P</code>. She, at first, said she doesn’t want to hear our message, but wants us to come back and help her.</p>
<p>But, she was excited to hear General Conference, and she listened to the afternoon session on Sunday.</p>
<p>So she called us afterwards and asked many questions, which I hope I answered clearly for her understanding.</p>
<p>She said she felt great hearing their words, but they weren’t like TVN (televangelists) pastors.</p>
<p>I nearly said, ‘well, we aren’t for entertaining and gaining money’.</p>
<p>But, I held my tongue because she loves watching TVN.</p>
<p>She’s progressing, slowly, but she’s opening up little by little. I feel good about her progress.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-2/seed.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p><code>A</code> and <code>Y</code> are doing great!</p>
<p>They loved conference, and are just soaking everything in like a sponge. I am so happy they’re progressing a lot even after baptism.</p>
<p>It was strange because we had a lot more less active/recent convert lessons. We committed two of our less actives to meet with the bishop, and we’ll follow up on that.</p>
<p>And our recent converts are strong as ever. It’s really too bad to know that it’s great that we do this, but this should be the job of the ward missionaries, home and visiting teachers that don’t exist right now.</p>
<p>But, the ward is working with it…we just have to be patient.</p>
<p>I expressed this concern to the second counselor Hermano <code>U</code>, and he said it’s just a long process with this ward.</p>
<p>Hopefully, it’ll be done by the time I end my mission. If not…I don’t like to think about it.</p>
<p>One thing I learned from Hermano Pablo <code>P</code> was that the reason why John the Baptist was the Elias, was that he was waiting for the higher priesthood.</p>
<p>He told me that he realized that Israel lost the Melchezidek priesthood when Israel idolized the golden calf, and so only the Levites up until John had the Aaronic priesthood.</p>
<p>So John prepared the way, but was waiting for not only the Christ, but for the higher power and authority of God to be restored through Christ and the First Presidency of Peter, James, and John.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Always learn something new every day.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I have been reading Jesus the Christ, and it is just full of knowledge waiting to be extracted and soaked in.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>It is so sweet!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It is truly inspired gospel knowledge, and it is really helping me understand the Atonement better and how it applies to me.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I love my Savior Jesus Christ.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I have also been reading of how I can be a better missionary.</p>
<p>And the Lord has guided me to read the great stories of Ammon, Amulek, Alma, Aaron (all start with A’s…hmm) to give me an extra motivation to do better.</p>
<p>I just feel the Spirit in reading their accounts, of how their efforts led to even greater things.</p>
<p>They endured a lot, a lot of suffering and pain and imprisonment, but came out on top.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I thought my life was bad.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It’d really be bad to be smitten on the cheeks and spit on by chief judges and left naked.</p>
<p>Wow, what great examples for me.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Life is great, and tiring.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We are being blessed with some cool potential investigators and are really receiving the Lord’s blessings in this area.</p>
<p>I don’t even feel like I’m working very hard, but I know I’m working smartly so I won’t burn out.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I love missionary work.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>In six days, my ten month mark! Oh my gosh! Time does fly!</p>
<p>I’m glad to know all is well at home. Stay safe, and I love you all!</p>
<p>Love,<br>
Spencer</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>letters</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-2/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2008 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-2/fountain.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>California Spring - It’s on!</title>
  <dc:creator>Elder Irvine</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-3/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><strong><em>I’m going ENGLISH!!!!</em></strong></p>
<p><strong><em>Yup, President wants me to take a break and go English. To the desert, going to be driving a Chevy truck in the middle of the desert. What luck, eh? I’m gonna be hangin’ with the Joshua trees.</em></strong></p>
<p>APRIL FOOL’S!!! Yeah, I’m kidding.</p>
<p>But, I really enjoyed this week.</p>
<p>Not as stressed, now I’m getting used to being senior comp and my comp <code>L</code> is way chill so he’s making it really easy on me.</p>
<p>I get all uptight sometimes but he’s cool with it so we get along real well.</p>
<p>Yeah…try to have a comp who hasn’t spoken much Spanish in about 7 months and having a ton of appointments and having to speak about 90% to start off the transfer.</p>
<p>Rough! But, it taught me I have to help him out more.</p>
<p>It’s funny what Kristy said- &gt; where’d all the money go?</p>
<p>Well, bought photos and a 100 buck bike.</p>
<p>Yup, that’s about it. At least I don’t waste money asking the parents to send stuff every week. :-) Oh yeah, Uncle David sent me 100 bucks too. How nice!</p>
<p>New investigators are falling into our laps, literally.</p>
<p>Because we took over the bike area (other elders didn’t work at all) we got new referrals.</p>
<p>Technically we got 2 new investigators but we have at least 3 others that we’ll have appointments with this coming week.</p>
<p>So the work is picking back up, and everything is calming down for me. I’m not all over my head now so…it’s all good now.</p>
<p>I’m so glad that President blessed me with Elder <code>L</code>, because if I had a pushy comp I really would be going nuts.</p>
<p>His Spanish is coming, so I’m really glad of his progress and now he’s really getting his confidence up (which helps a lot in teaching lessons).</p>
<p>I used to teach the entire lesson because he wasn’t exactly confident, but now he chips in once in a while and I’m turning more and more over to him.</p>
<p>I’ll have to let him teach more now we hit the 3 week mark together.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-3/flowers.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Well, no one is really progressing, with the exception of a few. The <code>Js</code> didn’t come to church because the father was working (that sabbath day thing doesn’t click just yet nor does the application of faith) and the mother was really sick.</p>
<p>She answered the phone and I thought it was the father.</p>
<p>I was like huh? who? oh…sorry…hope you feel better. A bit awkward at first. Alex <code>G</code> came to church with his wife (a member), as did a friend of a member whose name is Johnny <code>M</code>.</p>
<p>He’s progressing, he’s come to church two weeks in a row and we finally got an appointment with him.</p>
<p>He asked to get baptized, but I said just a little more preparation and you’ll be good.</p>
<p>He’s way excited! And, the non-member wife of a member has come to church for the last month, she even came without her husband yesterday!</p>
<p>After the baptism, we finally found an investigator!</p>
<p>She used to have a baptismal date, but went to Mexico and lost her testimony.</p>
<p>Now she’s asking, ‘which church is true?’ yet again. All the work that the other elders put in, lost.</p>
<p>We gotta start from ground zero again…man…why did she go to Mexico for two months?</p>
<p>Right before baptism?</p>
<p>Well, she’s a really good friend with a local member so we’ll see what happens. I’m afraid it’ll take a while until she gets her testimony back.</p>
<p>It’s sad to see that…Well, being senior comp means a lot of phone calls and appointments set, but I’m handing that over slowly to Elder <code>L</code> so I don’t have too much to do.</p>
<p>The sister missionaries had a baptism yesterday, so it was a good day overall.</p>
<p>We did some service this past week, more than usual.</p>
<p>On Tuesday we helped the amazing Sister <code>F</code> with weeds (she needs a lot of help in that department) and the next day we helped another elderly member pull weeds.</p>
<p>It was weird because we got their in street clothes ready to dig in and the sister missionaries were there in proselyting attire.</p>
<p>We were like…uh…Sister <code>C</code>? Hermanas? So they helped us weed too. It got hot too, that’s what you get when you weed in the afternoon.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>It’s all good!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We had some really great and spiritual lessons this past week.</p>
<p>The <code>C</code>s, just money in the spiritual department.</p>
<p>They always testify of how they’ve changed, how great they feel and that inner peace that they have.</p>
<p>And, we found out last week that Alberto’s brother wants to start listening to us. We’re already teaching Gustavo, Alberto’s other younger brother.</p>
<p>Sweet!</p>
<p>So we taught the third lesson, the Gospel of Jesus Christ (faith, repentance, the whole she-bang).</p>
<p>The first time, we tried to just go through it to finish it all. But, the Spirit was strong and they kept on saying of how the Gospel has changed them…it was beautiful!</p>
<p>Faith, repentance, baptism.</p>
<p>They said they really felt great after baptism and that they are really happy where they are.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-3/reeds.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Yadira mentioned how her faith has increased since their children, Adalay and Jeffrey, always say ‘let’s pray’ when they have a problem.</p>
<p>They were running out of gas, ‘let’s pray mommy!’.</p>
<p>She said it was great to see their faith, even as little children.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>That was sweet.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The next lesson was probably better.</p>
<p>They asked us how they can tell people that they need the gift of the Holy Ghost, and thank goodness for personal study!</p>
<p>I studied the Holy Ghost and how to describe it that morning, so I just whipped out some scriptures that illustrates the importance of it.</p>
<p>Both were in the book of Acts (a really great book by the way) and they were happy to find evidence in the Bible to convince their Christian friends.</p>
<p>These scriptures helped them understand the importance better, how Paul went preaching and found some disciples that were baptized after the manner of John, but needed the gift of the Holy Ghost (which Paul gave them after they were baptized in the name of Christ) which is found in Acts 19.</p>
<p>And, about the magician Simon asking for money for the gift of the Holy Ghost (Acts 8).</p>
<p>It was awesome!</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I just love them!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>They know the path will be hard, but they said they’re preparing for it. I can only hope that I’ll see them sealed in the temple this coming year…</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I’m so excited!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Our investigator Alex took us out to eat lunch at a local Mexican joint in Saugus.</p>
<p>We had a great time with them.</p>
<p>We joked around, and I think he’s opening up to us more and more.</p>
<p>We’re his friends now, and his teachers.</p>
<p>As usual, he made fun of me being Asian (actually they say I’m Chinese) and it was pretty funny for him. It’s kinda getting old now…but whatever makes people happy, right? Even my comp Elder <code>L</code> says it’s getting old after 3 weeks of hearing it.</p>
<p>We had the longest zone conference ever on Friday. 6 hours. Pure role-play.</p>
<p>I learned some things, especially how to get members comfortable in asking neighbors to listen to the missionaries.</p>
<p>Now I have an idea of how to get members involved, little by little.</p>
<p>I think it’ll really help this area, if I put it into practice.</p>
<p>And I felt embarrassed when Sister Goodrich called us out to teach in a role-play about how to really describe the Holy Ghost. I was baffled, as was Elder <code>L</code>, because I tried to play it off a scripture and it didn’t work.</p>
<p>It was a good learning experience, and that’s why the next personal study I studied the Holy Ghost.</p>
<p>I have to admit, little children have the hardest and deepest questions ever.</p>
<p>Our recent convert Lesley gave us a headache in our last lesson this past week, with all her questions.</p>
<p>She asked us,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>who does God pray to?&nbsp; Does he need to pray?</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I was like…uh…companion, do you want to answer that? I gave a neutral answer that didn’t satisfy me. I really don’t know. I just assume that he prays to his father, to his father…etc.</p>
<p>But I didn’t want to get into it too deep. So it was like ‘well we don’t know’. At least we’re honest.</p>
<p>Wow. She’s loving church though, so that’s good!</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Life is great! The work is progressing!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Rough…and I’m happy knowing that the <code>C</code>s are baptized.</p>
<p>More and more I feel that the <code>J</code>s will need more time…more time than I can really tell.</p>
<p>But they will be, it depends when they decide that Sunday is the Sabbath, that the Lord will provide blessings, and if they really want to learn more and progress by staying for all classes on Sundays.</p>
<p>It’s their decision, I’ve done almost all that I can.</p>
<p>I love you all! I’m glad you are all safe!</p>
<p>Love,<br>
Elder Spencer Irvine</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>letters</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-3/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 31 Mar 2008 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-3/flowers.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>California Sun Has Returned…</title>
  <dc:creator>Elder Irvine</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-4/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Dear Family:</p>
<p>Truman G. Madsen has written some sweet books, from what I can tell.</p>
<p>That is really great to hear someone with a strong testimony share their personal witness of our Lord Jesus Christ.</p>
<p>Lucky!</p>
<p>About the call, I’m broke right now because I got no card nor money…to get photos and stuff that I’ll need a little later on.</p>
<p>Oh well, I’ll wait for next week.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-4/flower.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Thank you so much for the Easter package,</p>
<p>I got it on Thursday I think.</p>
<p>I didn’t even know when Easter was when we made our plans this week, until about Wednesday I didn’t even know it was that close.</p>
<p>It was pretty good, but the work has been a bit slow this week.</p>
<p>But, it’s going to get better.</p>
<p>15 months until I get to snowboard…ahhhhh….and the sun is coming out.</p>
<p>Great weather.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-4/snow.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>So I’ve been stressed out a lot as of late because I’m the senior companion and my new comp is still learning Spanish. Not his fault, it’s just that it puts a lot of pressure on me to teach and to listen and then teach for understanding.</p>
<p>Every night I’ve gotten home, planned for the next day, and just got ready for bed.</p>
<p>I’ve had no energy lately to do anything.</p>
<p>It just takes so much out of me to be the senior comp and in Spanish work.</p>
<p>But, it’s getting better since my comp is slowly learning and catching up to speed in Spanish.</p>
<p>I really took my skills in Spanish for granted.</p>
<p>And my two native comps and Elder <code>H</code> who was at the end of his mission.</p>
<p>Yup, so I’ve just been exhausted.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Such is the work!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And I kinda let my concerns fly with some really cool elders in my zone the other day and they suggested a few things to help me cope with the new responsibilities.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>But, it’s really rough.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>This week went pretty well, I guess you could say.</p>
<p>Our best lesson by far was with the new recent converts, the <code>C</code>s.</p>
<p>Tuesday we had the bright idea to watch The Testaments movie with them, and we did.</p>
<p>They love movies, they have a room full of them!</p>
<p>It reminds me of back home a little.</p>
<p>So we watched it, and at the end we couldn’t say anything.</p>
<p>The Spirit was there, and they were both crying.</p>
<p>Elder <code>L</code> just quipped,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>‘well, there’s not words that can describe this right now’</p>
</blockquote>
<p>and we prayed and left them pondering and feeling the Spirit.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>It was pretty sweet.</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-4/shadow.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>But, we did get a surprise call from President Goodrich wondering if he could accompany us to our appointments on Friday night.</p>
<p>I was super nervous! I really like President Goodrich and all, but I was really nervous!</p>
<p>So we taught Alberto <code>C</code>’s brother Gustavo and his girlfriend Berenice, with both Alberto and Yadira there.</p>
<p>And President.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>Talk about a lesson with the best testimonies ever!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It went really well, just talking about the commandments of the Lord and it really was a good lesson.</p>
<p>Thank goodness President was there because Yadira basically called Gustavo to repentance without giving him much room to say anything else.</p>
<p>She was like, ‘well, we were married because we were previously living in sin’ and ‘you have a family now, with a little baby and the best thing to do is to get married’.</p>
<p>So basically she was very blunt.</p>
<p>One of the only times I’ve heard her be so blunt and I was taken aback.</p>
<p>So President just cooled them off with, ‘ain’t the baby just so precious’ sorta attitude and it really helped.</p>
<p>Gustavo told us</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>‘in 20 days I’ll let you know’.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>So we got a goal now for marriage.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-4/lake1.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Elder <code>L</code> froze because President was there, so I was on my own the entire lesson. But, I also froze sometimes because President was there. But, it ended up well enough.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>It was good though.</p>
</blockquote>
<hr>
<p>To be honest, Saturday really stunk.</p>
<p>I’ve had a few rough days in the mission field, and this is one of them. We had all our appointments set up in Saugus (15 minutes away from the house) so we figured to knock some doors over there too.</p>
<p>We found out that all our appointments fell through, and so it’d be a waste of time to just go home, put more study time in (we left during study time so we could make it on time) and come back.</p>
<p>So, we stayed at the other elder’s apartment over in Saugus and just rested.</p>
<p>Elder <code>L</code> had to call President and his other comp up in Bishop because some members were spreading some false rumors about missionaries up there, so he did that while I relaxed in their apartment.</p>
<p>Went to knock some doors, with mixed success because the layout of the apartments made it hard for us to distinguish which ones were duplex’s or a 4 apartment complex…it was the weirdest thing I’ve seen!</p>
<p>So we knocked, then went and ate lunch at the elder’s pad again.</p>
<p>Then, off to visit some members around Saugus and back home.</p>
<p>It was really a rough day, no one was home too because it was Easter weekend.</p>
<p>But, we got a few lessons with a local member and another less active (who fed us dinner before we had our actual dinner appointment- I was so full!).</p>
<p>It was a really rough day. I felt tired and overwhelmed, but that’s how the work is supposed to be, right?</p>
<hr>
<p>My comp is way cool, and he can deal with my stressed self really well.</p>
<p>I’m learning to take it a bit easier now, and he’s a reason for it.</p>
<p>I was wound up really tight for the past few months, and it really showed this transfer so far.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>He’s so cool!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>We get along really well, and he’s really humble about his Spanish abilities.</p>
<p>He’s too shy sometimes to speak, but then again I don’t want to be anal and push him way too much at one time.</p>
<p>So I’m going slow with him, and he’ll learn step by step. He’s a way chill elder. I’m so lucky to be here with him as my comp. It’s gonna be a blast this transfer!</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-4/AZ_Sun.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>I’ve been really thinking about this transfer.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I want to work hard</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I want to be obedient, but not robotic. It’s a really delicate balance, and I am doing my best to find the balance.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>It’s tougher than expected.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And talking over everything with the other elders in Saugus made me realize how stressful Spanish work can be.</p>
<p>Other elders were called Spanish but gave up after 3 months and are stuck in English for the rest of the mission.</p>
<p>I might ask President to give me a breather in English, because I’m really stressing out a lot and I don’t want to breakdown in the field.</p>
<p>But, we’ll give it another 4 weeks and see what happens.</p>
<p>And it doesn’t make it easy trying to gauge whether President should keep 4 missionaries or put in 2 more next transfer, and I have to gauge it for him.</p>
<p>It’s a learning experience for me, no doubt.</p>
<p>But I have really seen the blessings come,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I just have to be patient, remember what I have, and move on.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It’s a great experience though, and I just have to hold on and go forth.</p>
<p>We got a few more investigators this past week, and we could be having a bunch of success coming up in a few months.</p>
<p>Members trust us even more with the two apostates gone and so we got some referrals from them.</p>
<p>The members are slowly getting a bit better, and the greatest news is that we finally have a complete elder’s quorum presidency!</p>
<p>Now to get the home/visiting teaching done.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I’m a bit optimistic about these coming few weeks, but I can’t get my hopes up too high can I?</p>
</blockquote>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-4/sunrise.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>The work is going well, it’s just this past week that people have been busy with Easter stuff and the both of us have been exhausted.</p>
<p>But, we’re both adjusting to our new roles.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>It’s sweet.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I love you all, and I wish you all well. And I’m sorry Mom missed my emergency calls. Well, there’s…Mother’s Day!</p>
<p>Love,</p>
<p>Elder Spencer Irvine</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>letters</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-4/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2008 06:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-4/flower.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Rainstorm? in California?</title>
  <dc:creator>Elder Irvine</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-6/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p>Dear Irvine Family:</p>
<p>Well, the weather calls for rain to move in.</p>
<p>So it’s a bit misty and moist over here, and it’s a little chilly at nights again.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-6/acorn.jpg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Reminds me of back home actually.</p>
<p>It is a bit strange for me, but it’s California!</p>
<hr>
<p>I hope you all had a great President’s Day, because it was a pretty chill p-day.</p>
<p>Went to a member’s house to throw a birthday party for one of the elders in the zone and then off to play some basketball in the afternoon.</p>
<p>I really need to scale my basketball intensity back because my back hurts a bit after a good and hard game of basketball.</p>
<p>I’m getting better at shooting (finally!) but it’s not really good overall to have a sore back for the rest of the day and a bit the next morning.</p>
<p>Thank you for your package, I love the Field’s goodies!</p>
<p>As for pictures, I’m saving them up to put on a CD to send to you, because if I send a memory card they’ll get erased.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>But, I had my first baptism!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>It was a crazy day and apparently that’s how most baptism days go.</p>
<p>We got the baptism all planned out on Tuesday and used a member’s computer on Saturday to type the program up.</p>
<p>It was a bit hectic when we had to use the computer in the clerk’s office after church to print copies of the program.</p>
<p>Rushed to drop the other elders off then off to fill up the baptismal font then off to a lunch appointment then back to get the other elders to get them to the baptism and got there about 20 minutes before people were going to arrive.</p>
<p>I was so nervous we were going to be late!</p>
<p>So I hurried up and rushed and dressed in my whites, and just waited.</p>
<p>A good amount of the ward came out with less than a day’s notice (because we finalized the baptism this past week).</p>
<p>I was so nervous, and it didn’t help that one of the local members asked me,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>‘so, are you nervous?’</p>
</blockquote>
<p>and I was like</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>‘heck yes I am it’s my first baptism!’.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I actually memorized the baptismal scripture in the morning (not that hard) and right before the actual getting into the font I was thinking,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>‘Habiendo sido comisionado…’ in my head.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Hermanno <code>DLC</code>, gave a great talk on baptism.</p>
<p>Then, a spectacular talk by Hermano <code>PP</code> on the gift of the Holy Ghost.</p>
<p>Too bad it wasn’t geared for a 10 year old girl, but I loved it.</p>
<p>And right before the service started, my friend Elder <code>H</code> told me,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>‘don’t drop her’.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Ha. Just great!</p>
<p>So I walked down into the font and I just blocked everything out of my mind.</p>
<p>I said the prayer then I pushed her under. I hesitated after the first push then just completely immersed her.</p>
<p>I walked inside the bathroom to change, and I said a prayer thanking the Lord for His mercy to use me as His tool.</p>
<p>I didn’t even know that I was going to baptize her until Friday night and I didn’t sleep well Friday or Saturday (I didn’t pay attention to the mother’s response when we were going over the program that Tuesday- so much for listening skills).</p>
<p>It was amazing!</p>
<p>I just felt so great! I was really blessed that the program went really well and that I was able to baptize someone.</p>
<p>I just love it.</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-6/flower.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>And something funny that happened too was that our piano player is Elder <code>S</code> from Seoul, Korea.</p>
<p>Our ward mission leader went to tell him that he was going to start the meeting (Elder <code>S</code> was doing the prelude) and said</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>‘vamos a comenzar’.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Funny thing is, Elder <code>S</code> only knows English and Korean. He was like, ‘huh, what?’</p>
<p>Then my pal Elder <code>H</code> flew in and told Elder <code>S</code> that meant, we’re going to start.</p>
<p>It was funny for me.</p>
<p>I absolutely loved it, and I can’t wait to see if the Lord will bless me with more baptisms in the mission I am serving for him.</p>
<p>And yes, I did give her the necklace.</p>
<hr>
<p>These last few weeks have been depressing.</p>
<p>I didn’t have the Spirit with me much, because of my own faults and weaknesses and not being exactly obedient or hopeful in receiving blessings.</p>
<p>A bit pessimistic and human, you could say.</p>
<p>But, I have gotten back on track.</p>
<p>It’s really rough because the other pair of elders that I room with are not very obedient and play music that doesn’t invite the Spirit, they’re pretty irreverent, and it really hurt me spiritually.</p>
<p>It was a bit rough, and I do not look forward to having an apostate companion because it might just make me want to go home.</p>
<p>I was a little depressed these past weeks because of the environment that I’m in.</p>
<p>On top of that, my comp is a bit trunky, well he’s trunky so he could listen to whatever music and to some small extent date girls, but he’s still working so it’s good.</p>
<p>He’ll end his mission working, no doubt.</p>
<p>So a combination of things have been happening, but have only taught me to be patient, longsuffering, and kind.</p>
<p>Not exactly me, but the Lord is teaching me in a hard way. And I felt my language suffer a bit since the Spirit wasn’t really with me, but also because I was not in a great mood all the time and didn’t study as much as I should.</p>
<p>It’s been rough, but it’s getting better slowly.</p>
<p>And, these other guys might be moved out and we might take over their area, but we’ll see what happens.</p>
<p>It just means a lot more work! Yes!</p>
<hr>
<p>This week was hectic…if I would tell you all it’d take forever.</p>
<p>But, we had zone conference and a trip to the temple and were busy all week.</p>
<p>It was good, but it is very tiring!</p>
<p>And I just love the temple!</p>
<p>But now we’re only going 3 times a year so it’s a bummer instead of once every 3 weeks.</p>
<p>But, it means it’s more special.</p>
<p>It should be, but now it will be even more special.</p>
<p>And also, the wonderful Sister <code>F</code> had us over for dinner to wish me a happy birthday, so it was a very strange moment without my family.</p>
<p>But, I’d do anything for them!</p>
<p>They even made me a delicious strawberry and lemon-icing cake. It was so awesome! So I had a good and busy birthday!</p>
<p>The people that we’re teaching are progressing.</p>
<p>And, the <code>J</code>s came for the first time in almost a month (though late and gave me a scare), and our baptism girl Lesley also came late (really giving me a scare).</p>
<p>Also, another investigator came (they weren’t even home for our last appointment with them) and a former investigator came. <img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-6/temple.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>So we had 7 investigators without really doing much.</p>
<p>It was really like a wake-up call.</p>
<p>It was as if the Lord just said to me, ’wake up, have faith, go to work.</p>
<p>And learn from this experience.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>If the elect hear His voice, they’ll come.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Wow. I was really pleasantly surprised.</p>
<p>I am being so blessed right now…it is truly humbling.</p>
<p>The work is progressing, and I am seeing how good this area can become.</p>
<p>Yes, the ward has its multiple problems but it could be improved and replenished with new blood. I really would be curious to see what happens as the months roll on.</p>
<p>I love you all, and keep safe.</p>
<p>Love, Elder Irvine</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>letters</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-6/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Tue, 19 Feb 2008 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-6/acorn.jpg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
<item>
  <title>Ice Cold California</title>
  <dc:creator>Elder Irvine</dc:creator>
  <link>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-5/index.html</link>
  <description><![CDATA[ 




<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-5/canoe.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Querida Familia Irvine:</p>
<p>As for the overcoat, depends on how much it costs to send the coat.</p>
<p>If it’s a lot, I’ll just endure the cold because it’s not worth a fortune.</p>
<p>And, P-days are too short to get everything done including shopping for coats.</p>
<p>As for packages, it’d be great!</p>
<p>Talks on CDs, music, and whatever you feel like sending.</p>
<p>I still haven’t finished the food you sent me way back when, like the instant rice and stuff since the members feed us A LOT!</p>
<p>Please don’t send me too much this time!</p>
<hr>
<p>Pres.&nbsp;Goodrich probably said I’ll stay with my comp, who is amazing.</p>
<p>I’m excited.</p>
<p>Start the week off great, I love my investigators and I love teaching them with the Spirit.</p>
<p>We doubled attendance this week because Elder <code>N</code> and I visited almost every single person in the chapel yesterday.</p>
<p>Saturday was, by far, the best day even though it was the busiest ever!</p>
<p>We ended up going to a less active’s house, the <code>S</code>s, whose Christian daughter called us blasphemers not too long ago.</p>
<p>I didn’t want to go, but Elder <code>N</code> was like ‘c’mon Elder Irvine’ so we did.</p>
<p>We get there and knock on the door, the daughter opens the door and had us come in.</p>
<p>We found out that her mom, the member, nearly died half and hour ago with severe drops in sugar level.</p>
<p>And, her mom prayed for the missionaries to come.</p>
<p>Her daughter knew it was an answer to her mother’s prayer.</p>
<p>We helped her move some things around the home, and sat down to talk.</p>
<p>They gave us tamales and then, the bombshell.</p>
<p>The daughter said that her trials are overwhelming, and that she wants to read the Bible and gain comfort from it.</p>
<p>She asked us <em>gasp</em> to teach her from the scriptures.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>What a change!</p>
</blockquote>
<p>The first time I went there I nearly cried because she called us blasphemers, and now she wants us to teach her? Wow!</p>
<p>So that was a pleasant surprise (understatement).</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-5/orem.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<hr>
<p>We went to another investigator’s home, not home, so we went to give a blessing to a member in Canyon Country and took a 15 minute nap.</p>
<p>It was good, because we needed it later.</p>
<p>Zipped in, blessed her son with a blessing of comfort.</p>
<p>The mother is a perfectionist, poor kid, she was mad he wasn’t being the #1 student and was just being pretty mean in my opinion.</p>
<hr>
<p>So we zipped over to another member, who is really sick.</p>
<p>We gave her a blessing and left to find a referral.</p>
<p>We got lost a bit, and finally found it. Not home.</p>
<p>Along the way, we stopped the car when we saw two black hoodlums walking.</p>
<p>We asked them directions,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>‘Hey, do you know where West Ness is?’</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And the kid closest to us shook and freaked out.</p>
<p>Then they said,</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>‘Naw, man’</p>
</blockquote>
<p>And we finally found it.</p>
<p>It was hilarious! If you saw his reaction, oh my goodness! That made my day.</p>
<hr>
<p>Quick lunch then off to contact in the park IN THE COLD. It was at least 40 plus wind chill.</p>
<p>But, we found an elect family.</p>
<p>This entire week, we’ve had some trouble finding the elect.</p>
<p>We set an hour apart in a specific place to find an elect, and we finally got one on Saturday!</p>
<p>We’re going to teach them in the next few days.</p>
<hr>
<p>Frozen, but excited, we found another recent convert and cleared up some of his doubts about priesthood, then finally went back to Newhall, 30 minutes away.</p>
<p>Less active wasn’t home, so we went to eat dinner…which was just fantastic!</p>
<p>Eating dinner at the <code>U</code>s is like going to a buffett, he gives us a LOT of food!</p>
<p>And, he’s an RM so he knows what’s up with the ward.</p>
<p>He’s our ear, our inside man.</p>
<p>We finished the ward mission plan on his comp and gave it to him.</p>
<hr>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-5/snow.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>We got to the <code>J</code>s home 30 minutes late, but our member fellowshippers were there!</p>
<p>I love familia <code>C</code>! We taught and testified about the Holy Ghost, and the Spirit was strong.</p>
<p>We got home, planned, and crashed really fast.</p>
<p>I have never been so tired than I was Saturday.</p>
<p>And guess what, the mother, daughter, and son came to church yesterday!</p>
<p>The oldest son is in Mexico with the soccer team and the dad was busy.</p>
<p>But, they are progressing! I was so happy to see them yesterday.</p>
<hr>
<p>The Lord is blessing us with the elect, two days in a row, and we are still going to go out there and do His work. Regardless of what happens,</p>
<p>I’m going to be His representative and going to do His work and His will.</p>
<p>Something my comp pointed out to me was that we are literally God’s representatives, that people reject us, they reject God.</p>
<p>We can’t disobey the rules, because we are in His stead.</p>
<p>It’s as if we are Him when we are in the mission field.</p>
<p>It’s motivated me to be a better missionary, to actually make good contacts, teaching moments, whatever you call them, on the streets.</p>
<p>My brothers and sisters are waiting for this Gospel, I just have to testify and teach.</p>
<p>What a great message, what a marvelous work!</p>
<p>I am sad to say, I am hitting my 6 month mark.</p>
<p>I am sad, I don’t want time to fly so fast!</p>
<p>I want to go back to the beginning and do it over again!</p>
<p>I don’t want to look back and say…if I only had done this…or that…if I only had the knowledge I have now.</p>
<blockquote class="blockquote">
<p>I love this mission, I love this work, I, most of all, love my Savior Jesus Christ.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>He has blessed me with the gift of tongues, He has picked me up from the lowest points of the mission so far, and He has blessed me immensely.</p>
<p>How I love my Lord, my God! As Alma says, if I were an angel of God and go about with the trump of God!</p>
<p><img src="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-5/ray.jpeg" class="img-fluid"></p>
<p>Dad- I love you, my loving and righteous father. If only I could make you more proud, if only I could show you how much I miss you. Thank you for working hard, thank you for being who you are.</p>
<p>Mom- I love you, my exemplary mother and caregiver. I can’t say how much I appreciate your words, your packages, and most of all, your love. I miss you.</p>
<p>Steven- Don’t miss church! I love you, my caring, loving, loyal, and most of all, worthy brother. You are my brother, and I know that you are the best brother I could ever have. I love you, and keep up the good work.</p>
<p>Grandma- I love you, my always polite, courteous, humble, and unique grandmother. I hope that all is well, that you love your Japanese DVDs, and that you can look forward to my phone call soon. Only less than a month to go!</p>
<p>Kristy- I love you, just keep it up! It’s hard enough contacting for 3-4 hours, but the work will progress. I thought Spanish work is easy, it isn’t at all! The investigators will love you, the Lord loves you, and will bless you. The blessings are around the corner, as my mission president said. Just be yourself. You’d probably kick all the sister missionaries’ tail out here with all that hard work you do!</p>
<p>I love you all, and I’ll talk to you soon.</p>
<p>Love, Elder Irvine</p>
<p>P.S. If you could send my companion Elder <code>S</code> a Christmas card or something, he’d appreciate it so much. I know he would appreciate a card from the best family in the world! Thank you!</p>



 ]]></description>
  <category>letters</category>
  <guid>https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-5/index.html</guid>
  <pubDate>Mon, 10 Dec 2007 07:00:00 GMT</pubDate>
  <media:content url="https://spencerirvinereed.github.io/spencer/posts/Letters Home from CA-5/canoe.jpeg" medium="image" type="image/jpeg"/>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
